<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><!-- Created from PDF via Acrobat 
	SaveAsXML --><!-- Mapping Table version: 28-February-2003 -->
<root>
	<track id="rage" bindId="pathOfWar" name="Rage" kom="STR">
		<circle n="1" name="Rage" type="EX">You channel the barbarian rage,
			a state where you gain heightened morale and physical prowess. As a
			swift action, if you are not [Fatigued], [Exhausted], or in a rage,
			you can enter a rage, which lasts for a maximum of %3+CON% [Rounds].
			While in a rage, you gain a +%CRL% bonus to attack rolls and damage
			you deal with attacks, and a +1 bonus to combat maneuver DCs and
			Fortitude and Will saves. When you enter a rage, you also gain
			%2*LVL% temporary HP. These temporary HP are lost when your rage
			ends. You can always prematurely end your rage as a free action. When
			your rage ends (either before the beginning of your turn due to its
			duration running out, or on your turn due to your ending it
			prematurely), you become [Fatigued] for as many [Rounds] as you spent
			raging (minimum 1), and you cannot begin a rage on either the turn it
			ends or on your following turn.</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Powerful Rage" type="EX">Your rage gives you
			unusual physical ability equal to a creature much larger than
			yourself. You gain a +2 item bonus to Strength. While in a rage, your
			size becomes [Large] (if you are not already [Large] or [Huge]), you
			gain the normal +5 ft bonus to your movement speed, +2 bonus to saves
			against combat maneuvers, and 5 ft bonus to your [Melee] range
			associated with the [Large] size). While in a rage, you do not suffer
			any of the normal penalties of being [Large], even if you&apos;re
			normally [Large]. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Intimidating Rage" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter], when you enter a rage, you can attempt to intimidate a
			single opponent within 30 ft as a free action (as per the in-combat
			use of the Intimidate skill). If your intimidate attempt succeeds,
			that opponent becomes [Shaken] until the end of the [Encounter]. In
			addition, your bonus to combat maneuver DCs while raging increases to
			+2. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Greater Rage" type="EX">Your rage increases in
			potency. You gain %4*LVL% temporary HP per level when you rage
			instead of %2*LVL%, and your bonuses to Fortitude and Will saves from
			Rage increase to +2. Additionally, select one of the following
			abilities (this choice is permanent): - Hurling Charge: While raging,
			after making a melee attack as part of the Charge combat maneuver,
			you can use a ranged weapon in your possession to make a single
			ranged attack. This does not provoke an attack of opportunity. You
			can treat any square you moved into as part of the Charge combat
			maneuver as a square you occupy for purposes of the range, line of
			effect and line of sight of this attack. - Momentum Charge: While
			raging, if you use the Charge combat maneuver and your melee attack
			hits, you may immediately attempt the Bull Rush combat maneuver
			against the opponent hit. If your Bull Rush attempt succeeds, you may
			deal damage equal to your Key Offensive Modifier to that opponent.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Stubborn Rage" type="EX">While in a rage, you
			possess [Immunity] to effects with the [Mind-affecting] descriptor.
			In addition, your bonus to combat maneuver DCs while raging increases
			to +3. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Mighty Rage" type="EX"> The power of your rage
			increases again. You gain %6*LVL% temporary HP when you rage instead
			of %4*LVL%, and the bonus to Fortitude and Will saves increases to
			+4.</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Heart of Fury" type="EX">You are always
			considered raging. You can activate the Intimidating Rage ability
			once per [Encounter] as a swift action. At the beginning of an
			[Encounter], you gain temporary HP (as per Mighty Rage), and no less
			than 2 [Rounds] after gaining temporary HP from this ability, you may
			gain a new set of temporary HP as a swift action. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="dervish" bindId="pathOfWar" name="Dervish" kom="dex">
		<circle n="1" name="War Dance" type="EX">You can whip yourself into
			a war dance, a state in which you gain heightened morale and
			maneuverability. As a swift action, if you are not [Fatigued],
			[Exhausted], or in a war dance, you can enter a war dance, which
			lasts for a maximum number of %3+CON% [Rounds].
			While in this war dance you gain a +%CRL% bonus to attack rolls,
			damage you deal with attacks, and Acrobatics checks, a +1 bonus to
			Reflex and Will saves, and a +2 bonus to saves against combat
			maneuvers. You can always prematurely end your war dance as a free
			action. When your war dance ends (either before the beginning of your
			turn due to its duration running out, or on your your turn due to
			your ending it prematurely) you cannot begin a war dance on either
			the turn it ends or on your following turn. In addition, you are
			[Fatigued] for as many [Rounds] as you spent war dancing (minimum 1).
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Frenzied Strikes" type="EX">Your frantic
			movements become more focused and lethal. While in a war dance, you
			gain a [Bonus attack] whenever you take an attack action and you gain
			a 5 ft bonus to your movement speed, which increases to 10 ft at 4th
			circle and 15 ft at 6th circle. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Razor Wind" type="EX">Your whirling attacks
			amaze friend and foe alike, leaving vicious wounds at blinding speed.
			You gain a +2 bonus to Acrobatics checks. The first hit with an
			attack you make against each opponent each [Round] inflicts the
			[Burning] and [Bleeding] conditions on that opponent. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Greater War Dance" type="EX">Your war dance
			increases in potency, and you become adept at avoiding the sharp
			pointy bits of metal other people want to stick in you. Your bonuses
			to Reflex and Will saves while in a war dance increase to +2. While
			in a war dance, you gain 20% [Miss chance]. Additionally, select one
			of the following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Cloaked
			Dance: While in a war dance, you can use the Surprising an Opponent
			function of the Acrobatics skill as part of a move action without
			halving your movement speed. Additionally, whenever you deal damage
			to a [Flat-footed] opponent, you deal %KOM% additional damage.
			-Tendon Sever: While in a war dance, any time you hit a [Flat-footed]
			opponent with an attack, you inflict the [Entangled] condition on
			that opponent for one [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Unstoppable War Dance" type="EX">While in a war
			dance, you gain [Immunity] to [Binding] effects, and moving out of a
			square of difficult terrain does not cost you extra movement.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Whirling War Dance" type="EX">Your war dance has
			reached the point where you are little more than a terrifying tempest
			of blades. Your bonuses to Reflex and Will saves while in a war dance
			increase to +4. Your ability to avoid damage increases as well,
			granting a 30% [Miss chance] while you are in a war dance. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Dance of Endless Blades" type="EX">Your war
			dance is a primal thing of terrible wrath and frightening beauty. Any
			time you hit a [Bleeding] opponent with an attack, they are
			[Battered] for the [Encounter]. Additionally, while in a war dance,
			as a move action and a standard action, you move up to twice your
			movement speed without provoking attacks of opportunity. You may take
			an attack action during this movement, and may divide all of the
			attacks you are entitled to among any targets who were within [Melee]
			range at any point during your movement. Finally, you may enter your
			war dance as a free action. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="pathOfDestruction" name="Path of Destruction">
		<circle n="1" name="Cleave" type="EX"> Once per [Round], as a swift
			action, when you hit an opponent with a melee attack and deal damage
			to that opponent with that attack, you may compare your attack roll
			from that attack to the AC of another target opponent within [Melee]
			range. If the attack roll equals or exceeds that opponent&apos;s AC,
			you deal damage to that opponent equal to the damage dealt by the
			attack. This ability is not an attack. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Whirlwind" type="EX"> If you would make one or
			more melee attacks during your standard action, you may add the
			[Volley] descriptor to a single one of those attacks; this attack
			with the [Volley] descriptor is applied against every opponent in
			[Melee] range. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Disrupting Presence" type="EX">You are a living
			force of entropy, and creatures who attempt mental focus close to you
			suffer the consequences. For each opponent, the first time in a
			[Round] that opponent activates a spell, spell-like, or supernatural
			ability within your [Melee] range, that opponent takes %LVL% damage.
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Terrifying Presence" type="EX"> Once per
			[Round], at the beginning of your turn, opponents within your [Melee]
			range become [Shaken]. A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+CHA%)
			negates the effect. This application of the [Shaken] condition
			doesn't stack with itself, but stacks normally with other [Fear]
			effects. This is a [Mind-affecting] [Fear] effect.</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Path of Blades" type="EX">When you use the
			Charge maneuver, you can make a single additional attack with the
			[Volley] descriptor as you make the Charge; this attack with the
			[Volley] descriptor is applied to all opponents within [Melee] range
			of squares you move into as part of the Charge. This attack deals
			%3*KOM% damage. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Greater Cleave" type="EX"> Activating Cleave no
			longer requires a swift action, and it can be used any number of
			times per [Round] (though you may only activate Cleave once per melee
			attack you make that hits an opponent and deals damage to that
			opponent). You may only activate Cleave once per attack you make.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Deadly Presence" type="EX"> When an opponent
			begins their turn within your [Melee] range, it takes %LVL+KOM%
			damage and is [Battered] for one [Round]. This ability can be turned
			on or off as a swift action.</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="pathOfAncestors" name="Path of the Ancestors">
		<circle n="1" name="Lineage" type="EX"> Any effect that would heal
			you but does not originate from you heals %LVL% extra point of
			damage. In addition, choose one of the following options. This choice
			is permanent: -Guidance: You gain a +%LVL/2% bonus on
			initiative rolls. -Leading the Charge: When using the Charge combat
			maneuver, you ignore the normal -2 penalty to Armor Class. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Hard to Break" type="EX">Once per [Encounter],
			if you make a successful Fortitude or Will save against an effect
			that would normally have a lesser effect on a successful save (such
			as a spell with a save of &quot;Fortitude half&quot;), you instead
			ignore the effect entirely. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Readiness" type="EX"> You gain a +2 bonus to
			Vigor checks, and becoming [Flat-footed] does not prevent you from
			making attacks of opportunity or taking immediate actions. Once per
			[Round], you may make a Vigor check at any time during the [Round].
			This does not require an action. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Resilience" type="EX"> You gain [Fast healing]
			%LVL%. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Ancestral Blessing" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter], as an immediate action, you can reroll a failed save.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Greater Readiness" type="EX"> You are always
			able to act in a surprise [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Strength Unbroken" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter], as a swift action, you can begin an unstoppable assault.
			Until the beginning of your next turn, you gain [Immunity] to damage,
			[Binding] effects, and the [Dazed] and [Stunned] conditions. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="disciplineOfSerpent" name="Discipline of the Serpent">
		<circle n="1" name="External Techniques" type="EX">Choose five
			weapon properties other than [Arcane], [Barbed], [Distant],
			[Hold-out] or [Quick-draw]. At 3rd, 5th and 7th circles, you may
			choose an additional weapon property. Your Unarmed Strike natural
			weapon gains those properties. If you possess any other natural
			weapons, they gain any 2 of your Unarmed Strike natural weapon&apos;s
			chosen properties at 1st circle, and 1 more at 3rd, 5th and 7th
			circles. These choices are permanent. Additionally, whenever you
			switch to a weapon, you may grant it a number of weapon properties
			your Unarmed Strike natural weapon possesses. You may grant it 2 such
			properties at 1st circle, 3 at 3rd, 4 at 5th, and 5 at 7th. The
			weapon retains those properties for as long as you wield it. Attacks
			you make as part of a Disarm, Grapple, Pin, or Trip attempt deal
			%LVL% additional damage with the [Precision] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Internal Principles" type="EX">Your combat
			maneuvers, and opponents-attempts to escape or act in a [Grappled] or
			[Pinned] condition you inflict, have a DC of (%11+LVL/2+KOM%) This DC
			increases by 1 at 4th circle, and again at 6th circle. In addition,
			you gain access to the following special combat maneuvers, which
			benefit from the additional damage of External Techniques: -Pushing
			Blow: As a standard action, you make a single melee attack that deals
			normal damage. If the attack hits, the target must make a Fortitude
			save or be pushed 5 ft, and you can choose to move into their
			previously occupied space. If you choose not to move into their
			space, you may instead push them %5*CRL% ft in the same direction.
			These movements do not provoke attacks of opportunity. A successful
			Pushing Blow benefits from abilities that would enhance a successful
			Bull Rush. -Neutralize: As a standard action, you make a single melee
			attack that deals normal damage. If the attack hits, the target must
			make a Will save or take a -%LVL% penalty to damage for 1 [Round].
			This penalty does not stack with itself. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Open and Close" type="EX">You gain access to the
			following special combat maneuvers, which benefit from the additional
			damage of External Techniques: -Close Meridian: As a standard action,
			you make a single melee attack that deals normal damage. If this
			attack hits, the target must make a Fortitude save or be [Sickened]
			for 1 [Round]. -Open Gate: As a standard action, you make a single
			melee attack that deals normal damage. If the attack hits, the target
			must make a Will save or all creatures gain a +2 bonus to skill
			checks against the target and saves against the target&apos;s
			abilities for 1 [Round]. In addition, when an opponent fails a save
			against your Close Meridian, Disarm, Grapple, Neutralize, Open Gate,
			Pushing Blow, or Trip, you may immediately make a [Bonus attack].
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Ceaseless Flow" type="EX">Once per [Round], you
			may replace any one melee attack other than an attack of opportunity
			with any of the following combat maneuvers, at the same attack bonus
			as the replaced attack: Close Meridian, Disarm, Grapple, Neutralize,
			Open Gate, Pushing Blow, or Trip. If the combat maneuver hits, you
			can use Ceaseless Flow an additional time this [Round]. If you
			replace a [Bonus attack] using Ceaseless Flow, it still counts as
			your [Bonus attack] for that [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Stop the Breath" type="EX">Your combat maneuvers
			increase in potency: when an opponent fails a save against your Close
			Meridian, Disarm, Grapple, Neutralize, Open Gate, Pin, Pushing Blow,
			or Trip, it is [Flat-footed] until the beginning of its next turn.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Poison the Blood" type="EX"> Each time you deal
			[Precision] damage to an opponent with Close Meridian, Disarm,
			Grapple, Neutralize, Open Gate, Pin, Pushing Blow, or Trip during an
			attack action, or an opponent fails a save against any of those
			combat maneuvers during an attack action you make, that opponent
			gains an [Imbalance]. These [Imbalances] cause the opponent to gain
			various conditions, as below, and have no other effects on the
			opponent. [Imbalances] disappear at the end of each attack action,
			but conditions your opponents have gained from this ability do not
			disappear when [Imbalances] do. -Two [Imbalances]: The opponent is
			[Battered] for 2 [Rounds]. -Four [Imbalances]: The opponent is
			[Blinded] for 1 [Round]. -Six [Imbalances]: The opponent is [Slowed]
			for 1 [Round]. -Eight [Imbalances]: The opponent is [Nauseated] for 1
			[Round]. -Ten [Imbalances]: The opponent is [Stunned] for 1 [Round].
			If multiple opponents would gain [Imbalances] from a single combat
			maneuver, you instead choose one of those opponents to gain an
			[Imbalance]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="On Power" type="EX">: You can now use Ceaseless
			Flow any number of times per [Round], and Stop the Breath now affects
			any opponent you hit with Close Meridian, Disarm, Grapple,
			Neutralize, Open Gate, Pin, Pushing Blow, or Trip, regardless of
			whether they successfully save against it or not. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="disciplineOfCrane" name="Discipline of the Crane">
		<circle n="1" name="Fast Movement" type="EX"> You gain a %5+5*CRL%
			ft bonus to your movement. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Between the Raindrops" type="EX">You gain a
			+%CRL% deflection bonus to Armor Class. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Through the Clouds" type="EX"> You gain the Fly
			movement mode. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Deftly Striking" type="EX">As a standard action,
			you may make an attack action at any time during a movement, and
			continue that movement afterwards. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Journey of the Crane" type="SU">You can take a
			great step as with the long legs of the crane, seeking new challenges
			to face or new lessons to learn. Once per [Scene], as a standard
			action, you can use teleport, as the spell. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Gust of Action" type="EX">You can ride the wind
			at overwhelming speeds. %1+LVL/4% times per [Encounter], as a swift
			action, you can gain an extra move action on your current turn.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Phoenix Reborn" type="SU"> As the avatar of the
			crane, you become an entirely otherworldly being. Once per [Scene],
			if you become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you are revived
			with full hit points one [Round] after your death or knockout. You
			can choose not to return, if you believe that your impact on the
			multiverse is complete. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="disciplineOfDragon" name="Discipline of the Dragon">
		<circle n="1" name="Dance of the Sun and Moon" type="EX">You embark
			upon the path of the Careful Sun or the Reckless Moon. Choose one of
			the following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Careful Sun:
			Once per [Encounter], when you make a successful Fortitude or Will
			save against an offensive action that would normally have a lesser
			effect on a successful save (such as a spell with a save of
			&quot;Fortitude half&quot;), you may instead ignore the effect
			entirely. -Reckless Moon: Once per [Encounter], when you make a
			successful Reflex saving throw against an offensive action that would
			normally have a lesser effect on a successful save (such as a spell
			with a save of &quot;Reflex half&quot;), you may instead ignore the
			effect entirely.</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Obsidian Mind" type="EX">Monks learn to protect
			their minds from the clouds of fear. You gain [Immunity] to [Fear]
			effects and the in-combat use of the Intimidate skill. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Stance of the Falling Star" type="EX">When
			knocked down, you are quick to get up for another exchange of punches
			and kicks. You gain [Immunity] to the [Prone] condition. In addition,
			as a swift action, you may become [Covered] for one [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Diamond Soul" type="EX"> You have [Resistance]
			to energy and magic damage. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Cloak of the Sun and Moon" type="EX"> Your
			devotion to the Careful Sun or Reckless Moon provides additional
			benefits. Choose one of the following abilities (this choice is
			permanent): -Careful Sun: You gain [Immunity] to effects with the
			[Binding] descriptor. -Reckless Moon: Once per [Encounter], when you
			make a Reflex saving throw against an offensive action that normally
			deals half damage on a successful save, you may take no damage from
			that offensive action instead on a successful save, or take half
			damage from that offensive action instead on a failed save. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Jade Heart" type="EX">You can absorb dark and
			harmful energies without suffering any ill effects. You gain
			[Immunity] to [Energy drained] and [Vulnerability], and to [Negative]
			effects. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Scales of Gems" type="EX">Once per [Encounter],
			as a swift action, you may harden your hide to absorb devastating
			attacks without harm. Until the beginning of your next turn, you gain
			[Immunity] to damage and to the [Sickened], [Nauseated], [Dazed] and
			[Stunned] conditions. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="judgment" name="Judgment: The Seven Circles of Knowing">
		<circle n="1" name="Knowing" type="SU">You are aware, in the general
			sense, of the moral and ideological predilections of any sentient
			creature within a spread with a radius of %15+5*CRL% ft originating
			from you. This spread moves with you, is not a divination effect, and
			is always on. It does not automatically penetrate [Invisible],
			[Concealed], or Stealth, but if you can otherwise circumvent these
			effects, Knowing will function unimpeded. Likewise, you become aware
			of the likely major moral implications of your actions. Just how much
			you are aware of these implications is determined by the GM. You also
			gain a +4 bonus to Awareness and to Perception checks. This is a
			[Bastion] effect.</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Mercy" type="SU">Once per [Encounter], as an
			immediate action or part of another immediate action, you may prevent
			up to %3*LVL% damage that would be dealt to any ally within your
			Knowing. This can only be done as the damage is being dealt, but may
			be activated after you know exactly how much damage a given effect
			will deal. This is a [Bastion] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Grace" type="SU">You gain a +3 bonus to all
			saves, %2*LVL% additional HP, and gain [Immunity] to all [Fear]
			effects. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Requital" type="SU">Opponents who start moving
			within the range of your Knowing suffer a 20 ft penalty to their
			movement speed, for the purposes of that move. This does not affect 5
			ft steps. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Light" type="SU">You may now, at any time,
			illuminate the area around you out to the limit of the Knowing. This
			may be turned on or off as a free action. In addition, you gain
			[Blindsight] with a range equal to the radius of the Knowing. This is
			a [Bastion] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Endurance" type="SU"> The first time in each
			[Encounter] that you fail a saving throw against a harmful effect,
			the effect is negated without affecting you. This is a [Bastion]
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Allegiance" type="SU">You are indefatigable. You
			gain [Immunity] to [Mind-affecting], [Fatigued], [Exhausted], [Blown
			away], [Stunned], [Dazed], and cannot be knocked [Prone]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="bastion" name="Bastion: The Seven Circles of Protection">
		<circle n="1" name="The Shield" type="SU">As a swift action, you may
			create a spread with a radius of %10+5*LVL/2% ft plus 5 ft
			originating from you called the Bastion Aura. This spread moves with
			you. Whenever a spell of first circle or lower that has a duration
			targets you, if it is not a copy, you may project it. To project a
			spell, create a copy of that spell for each other ally within your
			Bastion Aura. That spell and each of those copies become bonded to
			one another and gain “When a [Dispelling] effect ends this spell, end
			all spells bonded to it,” that spell gains “When this spell ends, end
			all spells bonded to it,” and each of those copies gains “You gain
			this spell’s effect only while you are within the Bastion Aura of the
			ally who created this spell. ” Then you cast each of those copies
			targeting a different one of those allies. This does not provoke
			attacks of opportunity and counts as casting those spells only for
			the purpose of those spells’ effects and abilities of this track. As
			a swift action, you may end this spread. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="The Gauntlet" type="SU">Whenever a spell of
			second circle of lower that has a duration targets you, if it is not
			a copy, you may project it. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Mantle" type="SU">Whenever a spell of third
			circle of lower that has a duration targets you, if it is not a copy,
			you may project it. Each [Encounter], the first [Dispelling] effect
			made against a bonded spell you cast fails. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="The Armor" type="SU">Whenever a spell of fourth
			circle of lower that has a duration targets you, if it is not a copy,
			you may project it. Additionally, each ally gains a +3 deflection
			bonus to AC as long as it is within the Bastion Aura. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="The Soul" type="SU">Whenever a spell of fifth
			circle of lower that has a duration targets you, if it is not a copy,
			you may project it. Each [Encounter], the second [Dispelling] effect
			made against a bonded spell you cast fails. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="The Ready" type="SU">Each ally gains a pool of
			%LVL/2% points. Without taking an action, an ally may spend any
			number of points from their pool after they know the numerical result
			of a single saving throw, attack roll or skill check they made to add
			a bonus to that roll equal to the number of points spent. These
			points may only be spent while the ally is affected by the Bastion
			Aura. The pool refreshes each [Scene].</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="The Strong" type="SU">When an ally within the
			Bastion Aura is reduced to -1 or fewer hit points from 0 or more hit
			points, it gains [Immunity] to [Dying], [Unconscious], [Stable], and
			[Dead] for one [Round]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="heroica" name="Heroica: The Seven Circles of Ending">
		<circle n="1" name="The Blade and the Bow" type="EX">When you gain
			this ability, designate target ally other than yourself as your
			partner (you also become its partner). A creature with a partner
			cannot be designated as another creature’s partner, and no creature
			can have more than one partner at a time. Once per [Scene], you may
			designate a different ally other than yourself to be your partner.
			You and your partner both add %LVL/2% damage to your attacks. If your
			partner also has this ability, the damage bonuses stack. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Of Might and Guile" type="EX">Choose one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Might: As a swift
			action, if your partner is within [Medium] range, you may deal %KOM%
			damage to all opponents within your [Close] range of your partner.
			This damage ignores [Immunity] and cannot be mitigated or reduced. »
			Guile: You can spend a move action to double your partner’s critical
			threat range for one [Round]. Your partner also gains this ability,
			but cannot use it in a [Round] where you have used it. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Just and the Unjust" type="EX">Your partner
			gains the benefits of a Lesser item or Greater item you are attuned
			to as if they possessed a duplicate of that item and were attuned to
			it. You cannot choose a duplicate of an item to which your partner is
			already attuned. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="The Truth and the Folly" type="EX">Whenever you
			attack an opponent against which your partner took an offensive
			action within the last [Round], you may ignore the highest applicable
			[Miss chance]. Whenever your partner attacks an opponent against
			which you took an offensive action within the last [Round], your
			partner may ignore the highest applicable [Miss chance]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="The Quick and the Dead" type="EX">While within
			your [Close] range, your partner gains [Resistance] to all damage
			dealt by opponents within your [Close] range. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Aleph and Null" type="EX">When either you or
			your partner kills an opponent, you each heal 25 HP and may each
			immediately take two 5 ft steps. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="With Your Shield or On It" type="EX">You don’t
			die until your partner would also be [Dead]. This only works if you
			are within 100 ft of each other, and have line of effect. If either
			of those conditions ceases to be met, you die instantly if this
			ability was currently sustaining you. If your partner has this
			ability, it does not make you immortal. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="smiting" name="Smiting: The Seven Circles of War">
		<circle n="1" name="Skirmish" type="EX">When you miss on an attack
			roll against an opponent, add a +1 bonus to your attack rolls for the
			duration of the [Encounter]. This bonus stacks with itself up to the
			higher of 2 or %LVL%, but cannot be added to more than once per
			attack. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Conflict" type="EX">Your attacks gain a +%CHA%
			bonus to damage. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Struggle" type="EX">The second time you hit a
			single opponent during your turn, you gain a +%CHA% bonus to damage
			against that opponent for one [Round]. The fourth time you hit an
			opponent during your turn, your bonus to damage against that opponent
			from this ability increases to +%CHA*2%. These bonuses apply to
			damage from the attacks with which you hit the second and fourth
			time.</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Escalation" type="EX">Whenever your Struggle
			ability activates, you may inflict the [Battered] condition for one
			[Round] on the opponent you hit to activate Struggle. The duration of
			this condition increases by one [Round] for every time you hit the
			opponent again. Additionally, once per [Round], if you hit a
			[Battered] opponent with an attack, that opponent becomes [Dazed] for
			one [Round]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+CHA%) negates
			the [Dazed] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Annihilation" type="EX">When you Charge, your
			attacks gain a +%CHA% bonus to damage for the duration of the
			[Encounter]. This ability stacks with itself up to two times.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Scorched Earth" type="EX"> If you are reduced to
			less than half of your normal maximum HP, your attacks gain a +%CHA%
			bonus to damage for the duration of the [Encounter] or until you are
			healed above that threshold. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="War Engine" type="EX">Whenever you hit an
			opponent with an attack, that opponent becomes [Battered] and suffers
			a -%CHA% penalty to its AC until the end of the [Encounter]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="virtue" name="Virtue: The Seven Circles of Renewal">
		<circle n="1" name="Font" type="SU">Once per [Encounter], you may
			draw up an immobile wellspring of vitality called a font, which
			manifests as a low steady hum and a single spark of light. As a swift
			action, you may place it anywhere within %10+5*LVL/2% ft. Each
			[Round], at the start of your turn, an arc of restorative energy
			strikes one ally of your choice within your [Close] range of the
			font, and heals %2+LVL+CHA% HP. A font expires after %CHA% [Rounds]
			(minimum 2). Fonts do not occupy a square, and cannot be targeted or
			affected by anything but the Virtue track abilities of their creator.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Icon" type="EX">You may now place up to two
			fonts per [Encounter], using a separate swift action to place each.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Dawnsign" type="EX">Fonts you place now persist
			for %2*CHA% (minimum 4) [Rounds] and an additional font emanates from
			you passively, beginning on your first turn each [Encounter].
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Vitality Engine" type="SU">If any portion of the
			HP healed by an arc would have no effect on a target due to his or
			her HP being full, instead of simply being wasted, that target gains
			temporary HP equal to the amount of healing that would have normally
			had no effect. Unlike normal temporary HP, this stacks to a maximum
			of half the target’s normal max HP. This temporary HP lasts for the
			duration of the [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Holy Glyph" type="SU">Instead of its normal
			benefit, an arc from one of your fonts may be used to expunge any one
			of the following conditions: [Shaken], [Entangled], [Nauseated],
			[Dazzled], [Deafened], [Blinded], or [Sickened]. You can trigger and
			direct a single arc from one of your fonts as a swift action, in
			addition to the normal arcs at the beginning of your turn. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Star Spark" type="SU">An arc may be used to
			expunge any one of the following conditions instead of healing:
			[Stunned], [Slowed], [Battered], or [Dazed]. Additionally, any time
			you use your swift action to generate an additional arc, you may
			destroy any one of your fonts to create an arc that heals 50 points
			of damage and [Teleport] that ally anywhere within range of a
			remaining font. You may not destroy the font emanating from your
			person. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Rebirth" type="SU">You may destroy a font as
			part of your swift action to generate an arc that revives a [Dead]
			ally, healing the ally to 50 hit points in the process (if the ally’s
			maximum hit points are less than 50, he gains the rest as temporary
			HP). If you opt to do this, you may not destroy a font with Star
			Spark as part of the same action. You may not destroy the font
			emanating from your person. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="professionalSoldier" name="Professional Soldier">
		<circle n="1" name="Reap the Whirlwind" type="EX">You can, with
			minimal preparation and using only the resources at hand, create
			deadly ambushes for your enemy. You can prepare traps, which can be
			deployed in combat as a swift action. You can deploy one trap per
			[Encounter], plus one more for every four character levels you
			possess. A trap will remain functional until the end of the
			[Encounter], with some exceptions. Every trap has a unique effect
			when sprung, and while traps are normally visible, they can be
			concealed with the Larceny skill (as explained in Chapter VII). At
			1st circle, you have access to the following traps: -Tanglefoot
			Paste: Atomized in a fine mist that hovers in the air, this paste
			covers up to five squares in [Close] range of you at time of
			deployment. Each affected square must touch at least one other
			affected square. Targets entering these squares must make a Fortitude
			save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%), or stop their movement and become
			[Flat-footed] until their next turn. -Tripwire: A tripwire is
			stretched across a 30 ft line originating from target square within
			[Medium] range. The entire tripwire must exist entirely within your
			[Medium] range. Those attempting to leave a square covered by the
			line fall [Prone]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the [Prone] condition. A tripwire can only trigger twice
			before being destroyed utterly. -Fumigator: A fumigator can be
			thrown to any square inside [Medium] range, creating a 20 ft radius
			spread of with a thin gas that has mild hallucinogenic effects
			originating from that square. For each creature, whenever that
			creature begins its turn inside the spread or the first time each
			[Round] that creature enters the spread, that creature starts seeing
			double, forcing it to treat all creatures as [Fully concealed] for
			the next 2 [Rounds]. A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates this effect. A fumigator dissipates after 4 [Rounds].
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="A Personal Touch" type="EX">Grappling hooks are
			standard-issue for rangers, and for good reason. Once per [Round],
			you may replace an attack made during your attack action with a
			ranged attack at up to [Close] range at the same attack bonus as the
			replaced attack. If you hit, you deal damage equal to 1d8 + %KOM% and
			knock the hit opponent [Prone]. As a swift action, you may then
			immediately pull the opponent closer to you by up to %10+5*LVL/4% ft.
			A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Prone]
			condition and thus prevents the pull.</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Kept Secret, Kept Safe" type="EX">At will, you
			may use a move action to lay down a cloaking scatter of smoke, dust,
			and silvered shards to screen your allies. All allies within [Close]
			range gain a +2 bonus to AC and Reflex saves for one [Round]. At 12th
			level, the bonus rises to +3 and rises again to +4 at 18th. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="A Swiftness in the Blood" type="EX"> Once per
			[Round], you may take an additional swift or immediate action.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Into the Valley of Death" type="EX">As an
			immediate action, when a creature triggers one of your traps, you may
			place another trap. This trap may not be placed directly under the
			unfortunate soul who triggered this ability. You gain access to the
			following additional traps: -Razorpod Cluster: Once activated, this
			ominous metallic tangleweed splits into three razorpods — whirring
			collections of razor edges deployed to three separate squares within
			[Close] range. At the beginning of your turn, each razorpod you have
			deployed can move up to half your movement speed. Razorpods can move
			into a creature’s occupied square and creatures can move into a
			square that a razorpod is in, but due to their tendency to get caught
			on anything, two razorpods cannot share the same square. Whenever a
			creature moves into a square occupied by a razorpod for that
			creature’s first time this [Round], or at the end of your turn if at
			least one razorpod occupies the same square as a creature, that
			creature is dealt %LVL+KOM% damage. This damage ignores [Damage
			reduction] and [Resistance]. After dealing damage three times, a
			razorpod is utterly destroyed. -Remote mine: Remote mines exist for
			the sole purpose of delivering cleverly timed pillars of cheery and
			warmth-giving fire hot enough to melt steel. Each prepared remote
			mine can be deployed in target square within [Close] range. As an
			immediate action, you may detonate a remote mine to create a 15 ft
			radius spread originating from the mine’s square that deals %LVL*4%
			energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor and inflicts the [Battered]
			condition for two [Rounds] against all opponents within the spread. A
			successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the damage.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Bring the Rain" type="EX">As a move action, if
			you have a means of communicating with a creature, you provide that
			creature with targeting information for its abilities. This lets the
			creature use your location instead of its location for purposes of
			determining line of sight, line of effect, and range when calculating
			whether it can target a location or creature with one of its spells
			or abilities. This ability works over any distance. Each [Round] that
			you retain a Stealth check’s result, including the [Round] you make
			your Stealth check, penalties to Stealth incurred by the creature
			currently benefiting from the ability are also incurred by you. You
			may maintain this effect for as many [Rounds] as you wish by spending
			a move action each [Round] you wish to maintain this effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="The Sound of Cannon" type="EX">You become as
			swift as the terrible thunder you herald. You gain a +6 bonus to your
			initiative, and all allies gain a +4 bonus to their initiative,
			bringing your total bonus to +10. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="reignOfArrows" bindId="arrowsAndDaggers" name="A Reign of Arrows">
		<circle n="1" name="Dead-eye" type="EX">You fight best when you
			don’t fight fair. When you hit a [Flat-footed] opponent with a ranged
			attack, you deal %3*LVL/2% (minimum 3) additional damage with the
			[Precision] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Return Fire" type="EX">Once per [Round], when an
			opponent within [Close] range attacks you, you may make a ranged
			attack against that opponent that does not provoke an attack of
			opportunity. If your attack hits, it deals %LVL% damage and leaves
			your target [Flat-footed] for one [Round].</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Ricochet" type="EX">You can intercept any sort
			of projectile, given a chance. As an immediate action, you can
			intercept and hinder any ranged attack, spell, supernatural ability,
			or spell-like ability that would target or affect an ally within
			[Close] range. Make an attack roll with a ranged weapon you are
			wielding. For purposes of that offensive action, the ally can freely
			choose to replace its Armor Class or any saves it makes with your
			attack roll. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Missile Barrage" type="EX">Each attack you make
			is part of a carefully planned pattern of fire. Immediately after
			taking an attack action in which all attacks are made against target
			creature, you may create a spread with a radius of %5*LVL/5% ft
			originating from target creature, causing each creature in the area
			besides target creature to be [Blown away] in a direction of your
			choice. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="A Crashing of Heaven" type="EX">You learn to
			take aim, steady your breathing, and unleash devastation on your foe.
			Twice per [Encounter], as a move action, your next ranged attack this
			[Round] deals %LVL*4% additional damage if it hits. A successful
			Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the additional damage and
			prevents that attack from reducing your target below 1 HP. Whether it
			hits or misses, this attack inflicts the [Battered] condition on your
			target. This is a [Death] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Storm Bolt" type="EX">Once per [Round], as a
			swift action, you may make your next ranged attack this [Round] into
			a Storm Bolt; if the attack hits, your target becomes [Dazed] for one
			[Round]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the
			[Dazed] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Thus Always Unto" type="SU">As a swift action,
			you can sap the will and ability of your opponents with every strike;
			until the end of your turn, whenever you hit an opponent with a
			ranged attack, you may inflict the [Energy drained] condition on that
			opponent. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the
			[Energy drained] condition and instead leaves the opponent
			[Flat-footed] for one [Round]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="ironMagi" bindId="arrowsAndDaggers" name="Iron Magi">
		<circle n="1" name="A Cadence of Blows" type="EX">From the Tempo
			comes the simplest Chain component, which trades immediate
			opportunities for a long-term advantage by throwing an opponent off
			balance. A Cadence of Blows replaces a single melee attack in an
			attack action, and when activated, grants you a +1 bonus to attack
			rolls against a single opponent within [Melee] range and a +1 bonus
			to AC. These bonuses stack %1+(CRL+1)/2%. A Cadence of Blows can also
			be activated as a Chain finisher when you have a chain of at least
			one Link long. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Howl of the North Wind" type="SU">This explosion
			of the biting and arctic first wind can be activated as a Chain
			finisher that requires at least one Link in your Chain. You create a
			30 ft radius spread originating from you that deals %LVL% damage to
			all opponents in the area and renders them [Blown away] or [Prone],
			at your choice. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates
			the [Blown away] or [Prone] conditions. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Beloved of the Dirae" type="SU">You gain a
			[Bonus attack] whenever you take an attack action. In addition, you
			may call on the principle of lightning through the spirits of
			celestial anger called Dirae. This is a Chain component that replaces
			two melee attacks in an attack action to strike an opponent with a
			rain of sparks. You may make a single melee attack against a creature
			within your [Medium] range. Regardless of whether the attack hits or
			misses, you create a 35 ft radius spread originating from your target
			that lasts for one [Round]. For each opponent, the first time that
			opponent moves into or begins its turn in this spread, it takes %LVL%
			energy damage with the [Electricity] descriptor. Opponents in the
			spread at the end of the spread’s duration are dealt %LVL*2% energy
			damage with the [Electricity] descriptor.</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Scream of the Black Sky" type="SU">With the
			festering darkness of the second wind, you conjure a swirl of violent
			black clouds as a Chain finisher that requires at least two Links in
			your chain. Up to three target opponents within your [Close] range
			take %2*LVL% damage, and are [Blinded] for two [Rounds].
			A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the [Blinded]
			duration. Scream of the Black Sky may be activated three times per [Encounter]. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Staccato Blastwave" type="SU">As a Chain
			component that replaces two melee attacks in an attack action, you
			invoke the Principle of Thunder to create a ripple of violent sound
			that shatters bone and tears flesh. You make a single melee attack,
			which deals damage as normal, plus %2*(LVL+KOM)% additional damage.
			If the attack misses, you still deal %2*(LVL+KOM)% damage to its target.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Bellow of the Deep Earth" type="SU">Roaring and
			sudden, you call the underground current of the third wind forth as a
			Chain finisher that requires at least three Links in your chain. You
			create a 50 ft radius spread originating from you that deals %3*LVL% damage
			to all opponents in the area and renders them [Prone] and [Entangled].
			A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Prone] and
			[Entangled] conditions. Bellow of the Deep Earth may be activated
			three times per [Encounter].</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Magnum Opus" type="EX">All of your Chain
			components and successful melee attacks add an additional Link to
			your Chain.</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Roar of the Storm Lords" type="SU">Once per
			[Encounter], you may activate this ability as a Chain finisher that
			requires at least seven Links in your Chain. You create a spread with
			a radius of your [Medium] range originating from you, which deals
			%LVL*3% damage to all opponents in the area, and renders them [Battered]
			for two [Rounds], knocks them [Prone], and repositions each of them up
			to 70 ft each to squares of your choice. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the repositioning effect and the [Prone] condition. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="battleTempering" name="Battle's Tempering">
		<circle n="1" name="Rather Quick than Dead" type="EX">Moving out of
			a square of difficult terrain does not cost you extra movement. In
			addition, choose one of the following options. This choice is
			permanent: -Shoot First: You gain a +%LVL/2% bonus
			(minimum 1) on initiative checks. -Gain Ground: You can take an
			additional 5 ft step each [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Dive for Cover" type="EX">Once per [Encounter],
			when you make a successful Reflex saving throw against an offensive
			action that would normally have a lesser effect on a successful save
			(such as a spell with a save of “Reflex half ”), you instead ignore
			the effect entirely. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="For Ire" type="EX">You gain [Fast healing] %KDM%,
			and becoming [Flat-footed] does not prevent you from making attacks
			of opportunity or taking immediate actions. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Look of a Survivor" type="EX">You gain
			[Resistance] to physical damage. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="It Has Been an Honor" type="EX">You are a true
			expert at getting the hell out of Dodge. You gain [Immunity] to
			[Binding] effects. In addition, once per [Round], as a move action or
			as part of a move action, you can fade into your environment,
			duplicating the effects of the invisibility spell. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Ghost" type="EX">You resist magical and
			technological attempts to locate you. Items, spells, and supernatural
			and spell-like abilities cannot be used to establish line of sight to
			you. Divination spells cannot be used to track or locate you.
			Additionally, you ignore bonuses to opponents’ Awareness from items,
			spells, and supernatural and spell-like abilities. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="A Masterpiece in Violence" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter], if you would take 60 or more damage from a single
			attack, effect, or ability, you may immediately make an attack action
			against the source of the damage. If this attack action kills your
			target, you take no damage. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="esotericaRadica" name="Esoterica Radica">
		<circle n="1" name="Playing it Right" type="EX">Any rogue learns to
			use a few key skills without pausing to think about them. Pick two
			skills. You can take 10 on both these skills regardless of
			circumstances. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="When to Hold" type="EX">When it’s time to stand
			your ground, you trust in your uncanny luck to protect you. Once per
			[Encounter] per circle you possess in this track, as an immediate
			action, you may gain a +2 bonus to your Armor Class, Fortitude,
			Reflex, and Will saves until the beginning of your next turn.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="When to Fold" type="EX">You know the value of
			beating a hasty retreat in the face of danger. %1+LVL/4% times
			per [Encounter], you can gain an extra move action on your current turn.
			If you use this move action to move, the movement provokes attacks of
			opportunity as normal. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="When to Cheat" type="EX">Once per [Round], you
			may take an additional swift or immediate action. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="When to Run" type="EX">Sometimes walking away
			from a fight isn’t fast enough. Twice per [Encounter], as an
			immediate action, you can move up to your movement speed. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="An Ace to Keep" type="EX">You can be extralucky
			when you need to be. Once per [Round], you may make a hit with an
			attack you made that is not a critical hit into a critical hit,
			inflicting all normal effects of a critical hit. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Gambler’s Dao" type="EX">You’ve made it this far
			with unbelievably good luck, so you may as well keep relying on it.
			Whenever you roll a d20, you instead roll two d20s and choose the
			better result. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="assassin" bindId="rogueOffensive" name="Assassin" kom="dex">
		<circle n="1" name="Sneak Attack" type="EX">You know that a fair
			fight is a failure to plan. Any time you make an attack that hits a
			[Flat-footed], [Helpless], [Confused], [Dazed], [Entangled],
			[Exhausted], [Stunned], [Shaken], [Frightened], [Cowering] or
			[Panicked] target, you deal %CRL%d6 additional damage with the
			V: Classes[Precision] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Slayer’s Sense" type="EX">Once you go for an
			enemy, you’re rarely inclined to let them escape alive. You can
			ignore [Concealed] and [Fully concealed] when attacking an opponent
			you have previously damaged with Sneak Attack during the [Encounter].
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Blood Calls to Blade" type="EX">Any time you
			make an attack against an opponent subject to your Sneak Attack
			ability while you are not benefiting from fury bonuses to attack
			rolls, save DCs, or damage, you gain a +4 bonus on your attack roll.
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Menacing Presence" type="EX">The sight of one of
			your victims leaves their allies disturbed and vulnerable. Whenever
			an opponent ends its turn within your [Melee] range of another
			creature you have damaged with a Sneak Attack during this
			[Encounter], it becomes [Shaken] for one [Round]. This is a
			[Mind-affecting], [Fear] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Felling Strike" type="EX">The shock of a Sneak
			Attack often causes an enemy to open their defenses. Whenever you
			deal additional damage with the [Precision] descriptor to an opponent
			within [Melee] range with your Sneak Attack ability, that opponent is
			knocked [Prone]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the [Prone] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Battle Fatigue" type="EX">Even if an enemy
			survives your first strikes, you still leave their body battered and
			crippled. If you deal Sneak Attack damage to an opponent twice in the
			same [Round], that opponent is [Slowed] until the beginning of your
			next turn. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Exit" type="EX">Hell is one other person in
			particular — you. Twice per [Encounter], as a swift action, you may
			deal additional %5*LVL% damage on your next Sneak
			Attack this [Round], and cause the target to be [Blinded] and
			[Stunned] for one [Round]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			halves the additional damage and causes the opponent to become [Dazzled]
			and [Entangled], instead of being [Stunned] and [Blinded]. 
			This is a [Death] effect. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="swashbuckler" bindId="rogueOffensive" name="Swashbuckler"
		kom="dex">
		<circle n="1" name="Dance With Me" type="EX">Whenever you move at
			least 10 ft, your next attack this [Round] deals %LVL+KDM%
			additional damage with the [Precision] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Once More!" type="EX">When you spend a standard
			action to make a single attack that is not part of a spell-like
			ability or spell, and then move at least 10 ft during the same
			[Round], you may make a single melee attack at the end of your
			movement. This attack, called a Once More! attack, can be made
			another time at the end of each additional instance of movement after
			moving at least 10 more ft. The required distance may comprise a
			single movement or multiple movements (such as a pair of 5 ft steps),
			but a Once More! attack can only be made when a movement ends. If the
			movement is made as part of an action, you can likewise only activate
			Once More! at the end of that action. You may only make
			%CRL/2% Once More! attacks per [Round].</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Dirty Fighting" type="EX">Your speed and finesse
			leave opponents demoralized and bruised, even before they are
			defeated. The first time you hit any opponent with a Once More!
			attack this [Round], your opponent becomes [Battered] for two
			[Rounds]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the [Battered] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Kick Him While He’s Down" type="EX">Once you
			begin to throw down, you have a knack of taking the advantage and
			running with it. Once per [Round], after making an attack during your
			turn, you may immediately take two free 5 ft steps (even if you used
			or will use a move action to move) and make a [Bonus attack].
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Concussive Impact" type="EX">You disorient your
			opponents with lightning-fast strikes. If you hit an opponent with
			two Once More! attacks in the same [Round], they become [Confused]
			for one [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Panache" type="EX">You mercilessly take
			advantage of openings in your opponents’ defenses. Any time an
			opponent provokes an attack of opportunity from you, you may move 10
			ft in any direction before making your attack of opportunity. In
			addition, every time you hit an opponent with a Once More! attack,
			you may move the target 10 ft in any direction. This movement does
			not provoke an attack of opportunity. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Topsy Turvy" type="EX">Sometimes you roll with
			the punches and sometimes the punches roll with you. Your Panache
			ability may now move each opponent within your [Melee] range after
			you hit an opponent with a Once More! attack instead of just the
			opponent hit. Once per [Round] for each opponent moved, if your
			opponent is adjacent to an obstacle or occupied square and you are
			able to push them 5 ft or further, you may forgo any further movement
			from that activation of Panache to render that opponent [Prone]. A
			successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the
			[Prone] condition. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="demoMan" bindId="rogueOffensive" name="Demo Man" kom="int">
		<circle n="1" name="Smells Like Victory" type="EX">You love the
			smell of freshly mixed exposives in the morning. Or afternoon. Or
			evening, for that matter. Choose an elemental descriptor ([Acid],
			[Cold], [Electricity], or [Fire]). This choice is permanent. As a
			move action or a swift action, you can mix noxious chemicals into a
			vial, which lasts for one [Round], at which point it becomes useless.
			These vials can be thrown as attacks in an attack action, and you can
			throw as many vials per [Round] as you have vials to throw,
			as a ranged attack ([Close] range), with a +%CRL% item bonus to the
			attack roll. A target hit by the vial takes %LVL%d4 + %KOM% energy damage
			with the chosen descriptor, and starts [Burning]. A successful Reflex save
			(DC %10+LVL/2+INT%) negates the [Burning] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Flash-bang" type="EX">Once per [Round], as part
			of a move action, you can add a fuse to a powerful firecracker, which
			lasts for one [Round] before its volatile chemicals become useless.
			You can use the firecracker in either of the following ways: 
			-Flash Grenade: As a ranged attack, which can be made as part of an attack
			action, you can throw the firecracker at target square within [Close]
			range, which creates a 10 ft radius spread originating from that
			square. All creatures within the spread are [Blinded] and [Deafened]
			for two [Rounds]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+INT%)
			negates the [Blinded] and [Deafened] conditions. 
			-Flash Missile: You can affix the firecracker to a
			single ranged weapon in your possession or a vial prepared with your
			Smells Like Victory ability. The next time you hit a creature with an
			attack using either that weapon or vial, that creature is [Blinded]
			and [Deafened] for one [Round]. A successful Fortitude save 
			(DC %10+LVL/2+INT%) negates the [Blinded] and [Deafened] conditions. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Sticky Bomb" type="EX">It dawns on you that you
			might want to ensure a safer escape. %LVL/4% times per [Encounter],
			without spending an action, you can affix a pouch
			of entangling goo to a single ranged weapon in your possession or a
			vial prepared with your Smells Like Victory ability. The next time
			you hit a creature with that weapon or vial before the beginning of
			your next turn, that creature and all creatures within a 20 ft radius
			spread originating from that creature are [Entangled] for two
			[Rounds]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+INT%)
			negates the [Entangled] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="High Explosive" type="EX">Your most spectacular
			creation yet is so volatile you’d be a fool to carry more than one...
			so you carry two. Twice per [Encounter], as a standard action, you
			may create a 30 ft radius spread originating from target square
			within [Close] range, which deals %LVL%d6 + KOM damage
			to creatures within the area and pushes them to the closest square
			outside of it, knocks them [Prone], and leaves them [Dazed] for one
			[Round]. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+INT%) negates the
			[Dazed] condition and halves the damage. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Sapper Rods" type="EX">You’ve created bombs that
			undermine magic itself. Twice per [Encounter], as a standard action,
			you may create a 30 ft radius spread originating from target square
			within [Close] range, and choose to do one of the following: end two
			target effects created by spells or spell-like abilities of 5th
			circle or lower that have durations and that originate from a
			creature or square within the spread or targeted a creature within
			the spread; or end a single target effect created by a spell or
			spell-like ability of 6th or 7th circle or lower that has a duration
			and that originates from a creature or square within the spread or
			targeted a creature within the spread. This is a [Dispelling] effect.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Cluster Bomb" type="EX">The more explosives you
			can fit in one space, the better. Once per [Encounter], as a standard
			action, you can detonate a cluster bomb in any square within [Close]
			range, creating a 30 ft radius spread originating from target square.
			This cluster bomb has three of the following effects of your choice:
			-Vitriol: Creatures in the spread take %LVL%d4+%KOM% energy damage with the
			elemental descriptor chosen for your Smells Like Victory ability, and start
			[Burning]. A successful Reflex save negates the [Burning] condition.
			-Flash: Creatures in the spread are [Blinded] and [Deafened] for
			two [Rounds]. A successful Reflex save negates this effect 
			-Tangle: Creatures in the spread are [Entangled] for two
			[Rounds]. A successful Reflex save negates this effect.
			-Blast: Creatures in the spread take %LVL%d4+%KOM% damage, 
			and are pushed to the closest square outside of the burst, 
			are knocked [Prone], and are [Dazed] for one [Round]. A successful
			Reflex save negates the [Dazed] condition and halves the damage.
			-Dispel: Choose one: End two target effects created by spells
			or spell-like abilities of 5th circle or lower that have durations
			and that originate from a creature or square within the spread or
			targeted a creature within the spread; or end a single target effect 
			created by a spell or spell-like ability of 6th or 7th circle or lower
			that has a duration and that originates from a creature or square 
			within the spread or targeted a creature within the spread. 
			This is a [Dispelling] effect. 
			The DC for these Reflex saves is (DC %10+LVL/2+INT%).
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Show Them All" type="EX">They laughed you out of
			the university – but who’s laughing now? Once per [Encounter], as a
			ranged attack, you can hurl a bomb that is beyond the wildest dreams
			of your stuffy professors at target square within [Close] range. You
			can make this attack as part of an attack action. The bomb detonates
			in a massive 60 ft radius spread originating from target square,
			inflicting %4*LVL% damage to all opponents in the vicinity. A
			successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+INT%) halves the damage. 
			Additionally, the blast leaves a cloud of flaming debris throughout
			its area of effect that lasts three [Rounds] and deals %2*LVL% damage
			to any creature entering the debris cloud and to any creature
			that begins or ends its turn in the debris cloud. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="acrobaticAdept" bindId="rogueDefensive" name="Acrobatic Adept"
		kdm="con">
		<circle n="1" name="Just That Quick" type="EX">You learn to react to
			attacks with stunning alacrity, sometimes dodging a blow that would
			otherwise pierce your armor. %CRL% times per [Round],
			when an opponent who is not [Concealed] or [Fully
			concealed] makes an attack against you, if you are not [Entangled],
			you may make a Reflex save and use the result in place of your AC
			against that attack if the result is higher than your AC. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Evasion" type="EX">Once per [Encounter], if you
			make a successful Reflex saving throw against an offensive action
			that normally deals half damage on a successful save, you may instead
			take no damage. Additionally, you gain a +%LVL/4% bonus to Reflex saves.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Supersonic Man" type="EX">You gain a 10 ft bonus
			to your movement speed and a +1 bonus to AC, and you gain a [Bonus
			attack] whenever you take an attack action. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Don’t Stop Me Now" type="EX">You can slip out of
			any bonds, even magical ones, and dexterously dive over any obstacle.
			You gain [Immunity] to effects with the [Binding] descriptor, and
			moving out of a square of difficult terrain does not cost you extra
			movement. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Artful Dodger" type="EX">Your sweet moves have
			become things of beauty. You never provoke attacks of opportunity.
		</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="No Sell" type="EX">Once per [Encounter], any
			time during a [Round], you may make a Reflex save. You may use the
			result of this save to replace the results of any Fortitude or Will
			saves you make for the rest of the [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Faster Than the Eye" type="EX">Your exceedingly
			acrobatic movements, like the unpredictable movements of a fly, fool
			the eyes of those attempting to harm you. Whenever you use Just that
			Quick and your opponent’s attack roll misses, you gain 20% [Miss
			chance] for one [Round]. This stacks with itself, but not other
			sources, up to a maximum of 80% [Miss chance]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="tenNinjas" bindId="rogueDefensive" name="I Am Ten Ninjas"
		kdm="wis">
		<circle n="1" name="Smoke Bomb!" type="EX">As a ninja, you are
			well-schooled in the art of disappearing at a moment’s notice. As a
			swift action, you can create an obscuring mist, as the spell.
			Creating a fourth obscuring mist causes the oldest of your obscuring
			mists to disperse immediately. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Ninja Reflexes" type="EX">Once per [Encounter],
			when you make a successful Reflex saving throw against an offensive
			action that would normally have a lesser effect on a successful save
			(such as a spell with a save of “Reflex half ”), you may choose to
			instead ignore the effect entirely. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Shadow Step" type="EX">As a swift action, you
			gain [Blindsight] out to [Melee] range and may add the [Teleport]
			descriptor to any of your movements for one [Round]. Whenever you
			activate the Smoke Bomb! ability, you may activate Shadow Step
			without taking another action. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Hummingbird Stance" type="EX">You gain the Fly
			movement mode. In addition, as a standard action, you can move up to
			your speed and make a single attack at any point during your
			movement. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Flash of Shadows" type="EX">%LVL/4% times per [Encounter],
			as an immediate action, you can [Teleport] a distance
			up to your movement speed. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Paint It Black" type="EX">You can make a Stealth
			check as a swift or immediate action. In addition, you no longer
			suffer a penalty to your Stealth check for moving at more than half
			your movement speed. Once per [Encounter], you may retain the result
			of your Stealth check after taking an offensive action. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Void Disciple" type="EX">You are permanently
			[Invisible] and have [Immunity] to the [Revealed] condition. Special
			vision modes like [Blindsight], [Ghostwise sight], and [Tremorsense]
			do not allow creatures to ignore the effects of the [Invisibility]
			condition on you. As a free action, you can turn this ability on or
			off. However, you must still use the Stealth skill to remain fully
			unseen. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="fortuneFavored" bindId="rogueDefensive" name="Fortune's Favored"
		kdm="cha">
		<circle n="1" name="A Little to the Left" type="EX">You seem to
			narrowly dodge what would otherwise be lethal blows. Once per
			[Encounter], if you would be reduced to negative hit points, you are
			instead reduced or healed to 1 hit point and immediately gain a move
			action. If you have the Swashbuckler track, this move action triggers
			the Once More! ability (if you wish to use it). </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Improvisation" type="EX">As a swift action, you
			can grant yourself or an ally within [Close] range a +2 bonus on
			attack rolls, saving throws, and skill checks until the beginning of
			your next turn. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Gift of Gab" type="EX">By distracting your
			opponents with constant jokes, elaborate discourse, and simple
			nonsense, you gain a +3 deflection bonus to Armor Class and a +3
			bonus to Reflex saving throws. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Better Lucky And Good" type="EX">Twice per
			[Encounter], once per [Round], you can remove any one of the
			following conditions from yourself: [Battered], [Bleeding],
			[Blinded], [Confused], [Cowering], [Dazed], [Dazzled], [Deafened],
			[Entangled], [Exhausted], [Fatigued], [Frightened], [Nauseated],
			[Panicked], [Paralyzed], [Petrified], [Shaken], [Sickened] [Stunned].
			Activating this ability does not require an action, and can be done  
			even if a condition would normally prevent you from acting. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Changing the Odds" type="EX">Things that
			shouldn’t work in your favor sometimes do anyway. %1+CRL% times per [Scene],
			as a swift action, you can reroll a single d20
			roll you made after knowing whether that roll succeeds or fails. You
			must keep the second result, even if it’s unfavorable. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Never Tell Me the Odds" type="EX">Once per
			[Round], as an immediate action, you may add 1d4 to a single d20 roll
			you made after knowing the numerical result of the roll, and treat
			the sum as the new result of that roll. If the result of the two dice
			rolls together is 20 or higher, it counts as rolling a natural 20 in
			any situation in which a natural 20 would matter. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Roll With It" type="EX">Once per [Round], when
			you would take any amount of damage, you may take half that much
			damage instead. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="justBlade" bindId="sageWrath" name="Just Blade">
		<circle n="1" name="Grim Heritor" type="SU">As a swift action, or
			part of another swift action, you may form a melee weapon of your
			choice out of pure energy, though it may include a decorative hilt as
			part of your personal stylings. This weapon has the [Arcane] property
			and three other weapon properties of your choice, and is a Lesser
			item of your design with enchantments as normal for a magic weapon of
			its type (see Chapter XIII). These choices are permanent. This
			weapon, called your Grim Heritor, does not count against your normal
			limit of attuned magic items. When you gain your 4th circle in Just
			Blade, re-design this weapon as a Greater item, and when you gain
			your 6th circle, redesign it as a Relic. Though your Grim Heritor
			possesses the [Arcane] property, the weapon itself is a supernatural
			ability, and attacks with it benefit from magic weapon item bonuses
			to attack, magic item enchantments that trigger on a hit, and the 
			[Brutal] property. While wielding your Grim Heritor, you count as
			having a Good Base Attack Bonus (equal to your level). You may only
			have a single Grim Heritor in existence at a time, and may cause
			it to disappear as a free action. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Mental Thrust" type="SU">As a move action, you
			may cause target opponent within [Close] range to be [Blown away] in
			a direction of your choosing. If that opponent would enter and leave
			a square you occupy, it provokes an attack of opportunity from you
			before passing on its less than merry way. A successful Reflex save
			(DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates this effect. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Mystic Focus" type="SU">The burgeoning power of
			your art allows you to create an unstable circuit of arcane power in
			your Grim Heritor. You begin each [Encounter] with your Grim Heritor
			uncharged. Once per [Round], as a swift action, if your Grim Heritor
			is not already charged, you may choose a spell-like ability that you
			possess. If you do so, your Grim Heritor becomes charged. While your
			Grim Heritor is charged, you possess a 20% [Miss chance]. When you
			hit an opponent with an attack made using your Grim Heritor, if the
			Grim Heritor is charged, you may render it uncharged; note the result
			of your attack roll for that attack, and activate the chosen
			spell-like ability (if able) without provoking attacks of opportunity
			as a [Surge] effect. If the spell-like ability targets one or more
			creatures, you must choose that opponent as a target of the
			spell-like ability if able. If the spell-like ability targets one or
			more squares, you must choose one square that opponent occupies as a
			target of the spell-like ability if able. If you would make an attack
			roll for an attack against a creature as part of activating the
			spell-like ability, compare the noted result to that creature’s AC
			instead. If it equals or exceeds that creature’s AC, that attack hits
			that creature. Abilities and effects other than the spell-like
			ability’s effects that take place as the result of a hit or critical
			hit don’t activate as a result of this hit. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Vectored Thrust" type="SU">You gain the Fly
			movement mode. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Devastating Barrage" type="SU">You can
			manipulate the latent forces of the universe. Once per [Round], as a
			move action, you may create a line with a maximum length of 
			%25+5*LVL/4% ft originating from you. Creatures occupying a square
			in the line are moved to the last square in the line. You then create
			an implosion, dealing %LVL*2% damage to creatures
			other than you in that square or any square adjacent to that square,
			moving those creatures to that square, and knocking them [Prone]. A
			successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the damage
			and negates the [Prone] condition and the moving effect from the implosion. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Indestructible Focus" type="SU">You gain [Lesser
			resistance] to all damage. At the beginning of your turn, you gain a
			Grim Barrier that grants [Lesser resistance] against the next source
			of damage you suffer. Grim Barriers accumulate during an [Encounter]
			and stack with one another, but each time you are dealt damage, a
			single Grim Barrier dissipates. All Grim
			Barriers dissipate at the end of each [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Voice of Devastation" type="SU">You can call
			upon the fundamental truths of the universe and proclaim your
			enemies’ mortality. Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you may
			create a spread with a radius equal to your [Close] range originating
			from you that deals %3*LVL% damage to all opponents and renders
			them [Battered] for 3 [Rounds] and [Stunned] for 1 [Round]. 
			A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Stunned] condition. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="arcaneLore" bindId="sageWrath" name="Arcane Lore">
		<circle n="1" name="Black Tidings" type="SU">Once per [Round], as a
			standard action, you toss twisting gyres of energy through the air,
			dealing devastating damage. The actual blast wave takes one of the
			two following forms, which you may freely alternate between. -Dread
			Wave: The Dread Wave manifests as a wedge with a length of %20+10*CRL% ft
			originating from you that deals energy damage with the [Cold] descriptor
			or magical damage with the [Negative] descriptor, chosen each time you 
			activate Dread Wave. The Dread Wave deals %LVL%d4 + %KOM% damage
			to all creatures in the wedge and renders them [Shaken] for one [Round].
			A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Shaken] condition.
			-Hammerfall: Hammerfall deals %LVL%d6 energy damage with the [Fire]
			descriptor or physical damage, chosen each time you activate
			Hammerfall, to each creature in a target square within %100+15*LVL% or any
			square with line of effect from that square that is within %(CRL+1)/2% squares
			of that square. A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the damage. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Canto" type="SU">Select one of the two following
			abilities. This choice is permanent. -Red Hymn: For every five
			points of damage dealt to an opponent by your Black Tidings, an ally
			of your choice within 100 ft is healed for 2 HP. Abilities or effects
			that would increase this ability’s healing apply only once per ally
			you have healed with this ability per [Round]. -Grey Hymn: For every
			ten points of damage dealt by your Black Tidings to an opponent, any
			ally besides yourself of your choice within 100 ft may move 5 ft.
			This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="With A Word" type="SU">Whenever you use your
			Black Tidings ability, immediately after using it, you may [Teleport]
			up to 15 ft in any direction.</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Verso" type="SU">Sometimes the few must suffer
			in the name of your own personal and completely opaque agenda.
			Whenever you use Black Tidings, select one opponent who failed the
			associated save. This opponent is [Battered] for one [Round].
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Recto" type="SU">Recto improves the ability you
			selected as your canto. The following text replaces your Red Hymn or
			Grey Hymn respectively: -Crimson Hymn: For every four points of
			damage dealt by your Black Tidings, an ally within 100 ft of your
			choice is healed for 2 hit points. Abilities or effects that would
			increase this ability’s healing apply only once per ally you have
			healed with this ability per [Round]. -Silver Hymn: For every ten
			points of damage dealt by your Black Tidings, any ally besides
			yourself of your choice within 100 ft may move 10 ft. This movement
			does not provoke attacks of opportunity. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Bitter News" type="SU">Once every two [Rounds],
			immediately after dealing damage with Black Tidings, you may inflict
			[HP reduction] equal to the damage dealt on each affected creature to
			each affected creature. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Binding" type="SU">Select one of the two
			following abilities. This choice is permanent. -Glimpse of Madness:
			Any creature affected by your Black Tidings who fails the associated
			save is [Blinded] for two [Rounds]. -Life Fades: Any creature
			affected by your Black Tidings who fails the associated save is
			[Exhausted] for the rest of the [Encounter]. This is a [Negative]
			effect. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="forceOfWill" name="Force of Will">
		<circle n="1" name="Healing Burst" type="SU">By focusing for a
			moment on the mechanisms of creation, you can force a bit of life
			back into the world. As a move action, you may create a 15 ft radius
			spread originating from you, healing %LVL+KDM% HP to all allies 
			within the spread. This is not a [Positive] or [Negative] effect
			and can only be used once per [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="A Stitch In Time" type="SU">Time is fleeting,
			but you have learned how to warp it for just a second, long enough
			perhaps to change fate. As a standard action, you may create a 15 ft
			radius spread originating from you, which affects %1+CRL% allies
			within the area. Those affected may immediately make a single melee
			or ranged attack. A creature may only be affected by A Stitch in Time
			once per [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Stem The Tide" type="SU">Twice per [Encounter]
			as an immediate action, you may craft a shimmering rune of force,
			then bestow it on a single ally within 45 ft. You start any
			[Encounter] with one rune placed, and may have up to two placed at
			any given time. This rune serves to block half the damage that would
			be dealt against that ally by a single source, and then dissipates in
			a shudder of smoke. This effect stacks in such a way that someone
			with two active runes protecting them takes no damage from a single
			source, but cannot opt to split them across two sources of damage.</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Steady Old Hand" type="SU">You may use A Stitch
			In Time as a standard action or as a swift action, and the radius of
			its spread is increased to 25 ft. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Shields, Brace!" type="SU">Whenever an opponent
			sets off a rune from the Stem the Tide ability, that opponent
			provokes an attack of opportunity. 
			A successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates this effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Swift As Thought" type="SU">Whenever you
			activate A Stitch in Time, you may also activate Healing Burst at the
			same time without taking another action. Healing Burst can now be
			activated any number of times per [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="The Time Is Now" type="SU">The clock is but an
			illusion. Once per [Round], without spending an action, you may place
			the protective rune from your Stem the Tide ability upon yourself in
			response to taking damage from a single source after learning how
			much damage you would take. This does not count against Stem the
			Tide’s [Encounter] limits.</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="arcaneSecrets" name="Arcane Secrets">
		<circle n="1" name="Hungry Shadows" type="SLA">As a standard action,
			you may create a 15 ft radius spread originating from target square
			within [Medium] range, dealing %KOM% damage and inflicting a -1 penalty
			to attack rolls and Reflex and Fortitude saves to each opponent
			in the spread and a penalty to the movement speed of each of
			those opponents equal to half that creature’s movement speed 
			for two [Rounds]. This is an Evocation effect.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Space, Discontent" type="SLA">You gain your
			choice of the Lungbreaker or Stutter Step Arcane Secret (this choice
			is permanent). -Lungbreaker: As a standard action, you may create
			%LVL/4% (minimum one) 5 ft radius spreads originating from target
			squares within [Close] range. Each spread lasts for 4 [Rounds]. 
			Line of effect is blocked between a creature or
			square and another creature or square if one or more spreads exist
			between the creature or square and the other creature or square.
			Creatures on opposite sides of a spread are [Concealed] in respect to
			one another. Creatures within a spread are [Concealed] to creatures
			outside of it, and vice versa. For each creature besides yourself,
			whenever that creature begins its turn inside a spread or the first
			time each [Round] that creature enters a spread, it becomes
			[Nauseated] for one [Round]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the [Nauseated] condition. This is a Creation effect.
			-Stutter Step: As a standard action, you may create
			a 30 ft radius spread originating from target square within [Close]
			range, inflicting the [Slowed] condition for %LVL/5% [Rounds] (minimum 1[Round])
			on all creatures besides yourself in the area. 
			A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Slowed] 
			condition. This is a [Binding] Evocation effect. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Dweomertide" type="SLA">You gain access to two
			Arcane Secrets, Spellbreaker and Reweave. -Spellbreaker: As a
			standard action, you may end a single target effect created by a
			spell or spell-like ability of a circle lower than %CRL%
			that has a duration and that originates from a creature or square within
			[Medium] range or targeted a creature within [Medium] range. 
			This is a [Dispelling] effect. -Reweave: As a standard action, you may
			restore one effect ended by a [Dispelling] effect in the last two [Rounds]
			that affected a creature or object within [Medium] range. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Space, Twisted" type="SLA">You gain access to the
			following Arcane Secrets: -Revelation: As a standard action, you may
			create a spread with a radius of %5*CRL% ft originating from target
			square within [Close] range. This spread lasts for 2 [Rounds]. 
			While they are within the spread, creatures are [Revealed], 
			and if they are [Invisible], they are treated as not being [Invisible]. 
			This is a Divination effect. -Dark Tendrils: As a standard action, you may
			use Wall of thorns, as the spell. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Unbearable Lightness Of Casting" type="EX">You
			may activate any Arcane Secret you know as a swift action. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Gravity Smash" type="SLA">You are able to summon
			the strength of the earth itself. As a standard action, you may
			create a 15 ft radius spread originating from target square within
			[Close] range, which lasts for 2 [Rounds]. Each creature suffers a -2
			penalty to attack rolls, AC, and all physical skill checks while it
			is in the spread. Whenever a creature in the spread spends an action
			to cast a spell, if that creature has not made a save against an
			ability named Gravity Smash since spending that action, that spell
			has no effect. A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates this effect. Each [Round], at the end of your turn,
			Gravity Smash deals 35 damage to each creature in the spread. This is
			a [Binding] Transmutation effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Cascade Failure" type="SU">For each different
			Arcane Secret you’ve activated during this [Encounter], the save DCs
			of all your Arcane Secrets increases by +1, to a maximum of +4. For
			each different Arcane Secret you’ve chosen when activating the Mystic
			Focus ability during this [Encounter], your Grim Heritor gains a +1
			bonus to hit while it is charged with an Arcane Secret, to a maximum
			of +4. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="incantation" name="Incantation">
		<circle n="1" name="Incantation" type="SLA">As a standard action, you
			may either heal an ally or deal damage to an opponent within [Medium]
			range. You heal HP or deal damage equal to %LVL+1%d4 + %KOM%.
			Dealing damage to an opponent with your Incantation requires a
			successful ranged attack roll (this is not considered an attack
			with a weapon); healing an ally does not require
			an attack roll. Additionally, whenever you decide to use your
			Incantation, you count as having a Good Base Attack Bonus (equal to
			your character level) until the beginning of your next turn. This
			applies to any attack rolls you make as part of that Incantation.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Imbue Spell" type="SLA">As a swift action, you
			may spend a spell slot of any circle. If you do, choose a spell you
			know of that circle or lower which either has a Target listing of a
			single creature or has a listed Incantation version (if a spell fits
			both criteria, you must choose the Incantation version). When you hit
			an opponent with an Incantation or heal an ally with an Incantation
			this [Round], if the chosen spell is not discharged from your
			Incantation, you may note the result of your attack roll for your
			Incantation attack (if you attacked with your Incantation), and cast
			the chosen spell without provoking attacks of opportunity and without
			offering a save as a [Surge] effect. If you do, that spell is
			discharged from your Incantation. You must choose that opponent or
			ally as the target of the spell. If you
			would make an attack roll for an attack against a creature as part of
			casting the spell, compare the noted result to that creature’s AC
			instead. If it equals or exceeds that creature’s AC, that attack hits
			that creature. Abilities and effects other than the spell’s effects
			that take place as the result of a hit or critical hit don’t activate
			as a result of this hit. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Shaman’s Presence" type="SU">Allies within 30 ft
			of you have [Fast healing] %KDM%.   </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Guardian Spirits" type="SU">Once per [Scene]
			after making a d20 roll and seeing the result, you may reroll it as
			an immediate action, taking the better of the two results. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Shallow Grave" type="SU">Once per [Scene], as an
			immediate action, you can prevent an ally within [Close] range from
			dying for 1 [Round]. The ally ignores the [Dying], [Unconscious] and
			[Stable] conditions and has [Immunity] to the [Dead] condition for
			the duration of Shallow Grave, but unless the ally receives
			sufficient healing to raise their hit points above what would kill
			them, it immediately dies at the end of your turn after the effect
			expires. At 20th level, you can activate this ability once per
			[Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Twin Incantation" type="SLA">Once per
			[Encounter], as a standard action, you may activate the Incantation
			ability twice. You may activate the Imbue Spell ability without
			taking an action immediately before the second Incantation is
			activated; the spell that may be cast as a result is not a [Surge]
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Stolen Moment" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			you may immediately activate your healing Incantation upon an ally
			that has just been dealt damage or afflicted with a harmful condition
			or effect. This does not require an action. You may activate the
			Imbue Spell ability as an immediate action before activating the
			Incantation ability in this way; the spell must be cast and
			discharged. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="shamanPath" name="Shaman's Path">
	</track>
	<track id="shamanSpells" name="Shaman Spellcasting">
	</track>
	<track id="tacticalInsight" name="Tactical Insight">
		<circle n="1" name="Identification" type="EX">As part of a move
			action, you can attempt a Knowledge skill check of the relevant type
			against your opponent (Arcana against an [Outsider], for example). If
			there are several opponents of the same creature type, the ability
			affects all of them; opponents with different creature types require
			additional skill checks (requiring additional partial move actions).
			The DC of the check is equal to 10 + the level of the highest-level
			opponent of that creature type (minimum 11). If you succeed on the
			check, you and allies who can establish line of sight to you or
			receive your communication gain the benefits of one of the abilities
			that you know from the list below. You can make any number of
			Knowledge checks in this way per [Encounter] as long as you spend an
			action for each, but you cannot apply the same ability to the same
			creature type more than once during the [Encounter]. Opponents that
			join an [Encounter] in progress are affected by any Knowledge skill
			checks that were made for these abilities this [Encounter] that have
			affected opponents of their creature type. The effects of a Tactical
			Insight ability expire at the end of the [Encounter], with new
			Knowledge checks necessary the next time you encounter that opponent.
		</circle>
		<circle n="1" name="Combative Precognition" type="EX">You and your
			allies may gain either a +3 bonus to attack rolls or a +3 deflection
			bonus to Armor Class against opponents affected by your Knowledge
			check. You choose which bonus to apply when activating your Tactical
			Insight ability. When you gain the 3rd circle of this track, you no
			longer have to choose: you gain both benefits of Combative
			Precognition whenever you activate it. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Psychological Warfare" type="EX">You and your
			allies may gain a +2 bonus to Bluff, Diplomacy, Intimidate, and
			Perception checks against opponents affected by your Knowledge check.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Precognitive Resistance" type="EX">You and your
			allies may gain a +2 bonus to saving throws against effects used or
			abilities activated by opponents affected by your Knowledge check.
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Exploit Weakness" type="EX">You and your allies
			may gain a +2 bonus to the DC of any abilities you or they activate
			against opponents affected by your Knowledge check. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Advanced Insights" type="EX">Pick one of the
			following abilities. This choice is permanent: -Quick Insight: You
			can activate your Tactical Insight ability as a swift action. -Deep
			Insight: Choose one of your Tactical Insight circles other than this
			one. You increase the bonus granted by that circle by 1. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Countermeasures" type="EX">Once per [Encounter],
			as an immediate action, you may automatically cancel a spell,
			spell-like ability, or supernatural ability that an opponent affected
			by your Knowledge check attempts to activate. The ability
			automatically fails. The ability counts as having been activated for
			the purpose of any resource cost (such as spell slots), and if an
			action was spent for the ability, the action counts as having been
			used. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Unspeakable Secret" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter], as a swift action, you may divulge a secret so profound
			that it renders a single opponent affected by your Knowledge check
			[Stunned] for one [Round]. There is no save allowed, and if the
			opponent has [Immunity] to being [Stunned] the opponent is [Dazed]
			instead. If the opponent has [Immunity] to both, the ability has no
			effect, but you really should have known about its [Immunity]
			beforehand. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="bagOfTricks" name="Bag of Tricks">
		<circle n="1" name="Surgical Precision" type="EX">Once per
			[Encounter] per circle of Bag of Tricks you possess, as a swift
			action, when you create a spread, line, or wedge without a duration,
			you may remove any number of squares from the area of the effect or
			rearrange them so long as each square in the area of the effect is
			adjacent to at least one other square in the area of the effect. Each
			square must be within range of the square or creature from which the
			spread, line, or wedge originates if the effect has a range, or
			within a distance from the square or creature from which the spread,
			line, or wedge originates equal to its length or radius if it does
			not. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Early Warning" type="EX">You and all allies
			within 30 ft gain a +%LVL/4% (minimum 1) bonus to initiative checks. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Bait and Switch" type="SU">%LVL/4% times per
			[Encounter] as a move action, if you have line of sight to two allies
			who are each within %10*LVL% ft of your location,
			you can switch the positions of those two allies. You can use this
			ability to switch yourself with another ally. This is a [Warp]
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="The Enemy You Know" type="SU">You have
			[Resistance] to energy and magic damage. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Dweomerbreaker" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			as a standard action, you may empower the attacks of allies within 30
			ft until the beginning of your next turn. The first time each ally
			under this effect hits an opponent with an attack, they may end a
			single target effect created by a spell or spell-like ability that
			has a duration and that originates from the opponent or targeted the
			opponent. This is a [Dispelling] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Saw That Coming" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			as an immediate action, you can negate an offensive action that
			targets you specifically. This includes targeted spells, abilities,
			or attacks, but not area effects. The offensive action still counts
			as having been activated for the purpose of any resource cost (such
			as spell slots), and if an action was spent for the offensive action,
			that action counts as having been used. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Checkmate" type="SU">Once per [Encounter], as a
			standard action, you can imprison an opponent within your [Close]
			range for the next 2 [Rounds]. The opponent is incapable of acting or
			perceiving its surroundings, but it gains [Immunity] to damage and
			[HP reduction], it cannot be targeted by an attack or ability, and
			line of effect is blocked between the creature and any attack,
			ability, or effect. A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates this effect, but leaves your target [Dazed] for 1[Round]. 
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="tacticianSpells" name="Tactician Spellcasting">
	</track>
	<track id="chirurgicPoet" name="Chirurgic Poet">
		<circle n="1" name="Dream of Hope" type="SU">As a free action, if
			your maximum hit points are one or higher, you may suffer an amount
			of [HP reduction] no less than 1 and no greater than %KOM% to heal
			a target ally within [Close] range by twice that amount. This can
			cause your [HP reduction] to exceed half of your maximum HP.
			Abilities or effects that would increase this ability’s healing apply
			only once per target you have healed per [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="The Dream Endures" type="SU">For every 15 points
			of [HP reduction] you possess, you gain a +2 deflection bonus to AC,
			or your existing deflection bonus from The Dream Endures increases by
			2, up to a maximum bonus of %LVL/2% (minimum 2). This
			deflection bonus expires at the end of the [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The World Bends" type="SU">Whenever you suffer
			%KOM% points of [HP reduction] from Dream of Hope, you may move one
			creature within [Close] range up to 10 ft. This movement does not
			provoke attacks of opportunity. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="The Heart Beckons" type="SU">Whenever you heal
			an ally with Dream of Hope by any amount, an intangible dream-spirit
			lingers to aid them, remaining until it is expended or a single
			attack deals more damage to the ally than that amount. The spirit has
			no combat statistics, but as long as it remains, that ally may expend
			it as a swift action, creating a spread with a radius of that ally’s
			[Close] range originating from that ally that inflicts [Entangled]
			for one [Round] on all opponents within the area. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="The Mind Hardens" type="SU">You have
			[Resistance] to your choice of either physical damage or magic damage
			and energy damage. You may switch your choice of [Resistance] every
			time The Dream Endures activates. The [Resistance] remains until it
			is switched again. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="The Soul Sustains" type="SU">Opponents cannot
			score critical hits against you. Additionally, every time you score a
			critical hit, or an opponent would normally score a critical hit
			against you, you may increase the maximum HP of all allies in [Melee]
			range by %LVL% until the end of the [Encounter]. This
			may not increase a creature’s maximum HP above twice its normal
			maximum. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="The Skies Answer" type="SU">Your Dream of Hope
			and The World Bends abilities now affect all allies within [Close]
			range in addition to any creatures they would normally affect, if
			any. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="combatAlchemist" name="Combat Alchemist" tam="spell">
		<circle n="1" name="Lesser Brewing" type="EX">You have the ability
			to create Brews: potent but short-lived magical concoctions. These
			concoctions come in three varieties: potions for drinking, poisons
			that are applied to weapons, and cocktails for throwing into battle.
			At the beginning of each [Scene], you choose %3+2*CRL% Brews.
			The chosen Brews are prepared until the end of the [Scene]. At first,
			you can prepare only Lesser Brews, but you learn to prepare other
			brews at later circles. Prepared Brews must be primed before they can
			be used. You can prime a prepared Brew for imminent use as a move
			action. Once a Brew is primed, any creature can use it: a creature
			can drink a potion to gain its benefit, apply a poison to its weapon
			to increase its potency, or pass any Brew to an ally within [Melee]
			range as part of a move action (including the one used to prime it).
			A primed Brew not used by the end of the [Encounter] is wasted. A
			creature or weapon, respectively, may benefit from more than one
			potion or poison at a time but cannot benefit from multiple uses of
			the same potion or poison simultaneously. A poison that has an effect
			when a creature is hit by the affected weapon and allows that
			creature to make a saving throw cannot affect a single creature more
			than once per [Round]. Whenever you make an attack action, you may
			replace any number of attacks with an equal number of cocktail
			throws, each targeting a square within [Close] range. These throws
			provoke attacks of opportunity. Unless otherwise noted, the effects
			of any Brew used last until the end of the [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Transform" type="SU">Your knowledge of esoteric
			sciences includes the nature of things as well as the supernature of
			things. You begin each [Encounter] with a %CRL% transmutation points.
			Additionally, you gain the following abilities: -Exclusion
			Principle: As an immediate action, when an ally within [Long] range
			uses a spell, spell-like ability, or supernatural ability with an
			area of effect, you may spend one transmutation point to exclude any
			number of creatures from the effect. -Conservation of Energy: As a
			standard action, you may spend one transmutation point to deal
			%CRL%d10 damage to one creature within [Medium] range and
			heal another creature within [Medium] range a number of hit
			points equal to the damage dealt. A successful Fortitude save negates
			this effect.
			-Assisted Entanglement: As a standard action, you may spend one transmutation
			point to have two target creatures within [Close] range
			simultaneously [Teleport] into each other’s squares. The
			destination squares may be occupied, but only by another target of
			this ability, and only if both targets leave their squares as part of
			this ability. A successful Reflex save negates this ability. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Greater Brewing" type="EX">You can now prepare
			Greater Brews in addition to Lesser Brews. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Relic Brewing" type="EX"> You can now prepare
			Relic Brews in addition to Lesser Brews and Greater Brews. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Transmute" type="SU">Your mastery of arcane
			structures continues to grow. You gain the following abilities: »
			Equivalent Exchange: As an immediate action, when an offensive action
			originating from a creature within your [Medium] range, or whose
			target is within your [Medium] range, would deal energy damage with
			the [Acid], [Cold], [Electricity], or [Fire] descriptors, you may
			spend two transmutation points to have that damage lose those
			descriptors and gain the [Acid], [Cold], [Electricity], or [Fire]
			descriptor instead. -Nonlocality: As a standard action, you may
			spend two transmutation points to move the area of any ongoing
			area-affecting spell, spell-like ability, or supernatural ability
			within [Close] range to any other location within [Close] range to
			which you have line of sight and line of effect. The effect’s creator
			may make a Will save. A successful Will save negates this ability.
			You cannot move an ongoing area effect originating from a creature. 
			-Philosopher’s Stone: As a standard action, you may spend two
			transmutation points to transmute the equipment of target creature in
			[Close] range to heavy and largely useless gold. The target is
			[Slowed], the target’s item bonus to AC from armor is halved, the
			target’s deflection bonus to AC from a shield is halved, and if the
			target is wielding a weapon other than a natural weapon, that weapon
			loses two weapon properties of the target’s choice and the target
			takes a -1 penalty to attack rolls made using that weapon. These
			effects last until the end of the [Encounter]. The target may make a
			Fortitude save, a Reflex save, and a Will save. A successful
			Fortitude save prevents the target’s item bonus to AC from armor from
			being halved. A successful Reflex save prevents the target’s
			deflection bonus to AC from a shield from being halved. A successful
			Will save negates the loss of weapon properties and the penalty to
			attack rolls. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Artifact Brewing" type="EX">You can now prepare
			Artifact Brews in addition to Lesser, Greater and Relic Brews. When
			an artifact poison or potion is applied to a creature or weapon, the
			duration of any artifact poison or potion already affecting the same
			target ends. After a creature fails its save against a particular
			artifact poison, it can’t be affected by that poison again until the
			end of the [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Transcend" type="SU">Your mastery of the
			esoteric is absolute. You gain the following abilities: -Momentum
			Transfer: As an immediate action, you may spend four transmutation
			points to cause a creature within [Long] range to be unable to take
			standard actions for 1 [Round]. A successful Will save negates this
			effect. If you cause a creature
			using an ability that requires a standard action to use to be unable
			to take standard actions, that creature does not use that ability or
			expend any uses of that ability. -Necromuscular Stimulation: When
			you die, if you have a Lifewine Brew prepared but not primed, you may
			spend four transmutation points to cause the Lifewine Brew to boil
			over into a revivifying gas. If you do so, the Lifewine is consumed,
			and you are reborn in a bolt of alchemical glory on your next turn
			with current hit points equal to half of your maximum hit points.
			Neuromuscular Stimulation can only be used once per [Scene].
			-Carbonization: As a standard action, you may spend four transmutation
			points to inflict a flesh-hardening curse on a single creature in
			[Close] range. The creature is [Entangled]. A successful Fortitude
			save negates the [Entangled] condition. Each subsequent [Round], at
			the beginning of your turn, the creature makes an additional
			Fortitude save, the effects of which vary depending on its current
			state, as listed below:Not [Entangled] or [Slowed]: The creature
			becomes [Entangled]. A successful save negates the [Entangled]
			condition and ends the Carbonization ability. [Entangled]: The
			creature becomes [Slowed]. A successful Fortitude save negates the
			[Slowed] condition, and removes the [Entangled] condition if it was
			caused by Carbonization. [Slowed]: The creature becomes [Entangled].
			A successful Fortitude save negates the [Entangled] condition, and
			removes the [Slowed] condition if it was caused by Carbonization.
			Both [Entangled] and [Slowed]: The creature becomes [Petrified] for
			three [Rounds]. While the affected creature is [Petrified], it does
			not make saves against Carbonization. It still makes saves against
			the [Petrified] condition normally. A successful Fortitude save
			negates the [Petrified] condition, and removes the [Slowed] condition
			if it was caused by Carbonization. This effect, and all conditions
			inflicted by it, end either once the target creature has been
			[Petrified] by it for 3 [Rounds], or at the end of the [Encounter]. »
			Probability Redistribution: As a standard action, you may choose two
			creatures, causing an exchange of one condition or temporary magical
			effects from each to the other. Viable effects include spells and
			spell-like ability targeting that creature with a duration measured
			in [Rounds], an [Encounter] or a [Scene], and the following
			conditions: [Battered], [Bleeding], [Blinded], [Confused],
			[Cowering], [Dazed], [Dazzled], [Deafened], [Entangled], [Exhausted],
			[Fatigued], [Frightened], [Nauseated], [Panicked], [Paralyzed],
			[Petrified], [Shaken], [Sickened] or [Stunned]. If only one of your
			targets is under a valid effect, you only move a single valid effect
			from that target to the other target. Both targets must be within
			[Medium] range, and each can make a Will save to negate this effect.
			If either succeeds, Probability Redistribution fails entirely.
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="elementalist" name="Elementalist" tam="spell">
		<circle n="1" name="Elemental Burst" type="SLA">You can summon bursts
			of elemental energy. At will, you may deal %LVL%d6 + %TAM% energy damage
			to each creature in target square within [Close] range. A successful save
			halves the damage. The save required is Reflex if you channel [Electricity]
			or [Fire], or Fortitude if you channel [Acid] or [Cold]. At 4th circle, you can
			activate this ability as a swift action once per [Round], in addition
			to activating it as a standard action. In addition, whenever one of
			your abilities affects a creature with [Immunity] to your chosen
			element’s descriptor, you may choose to treat their [Immunity] as if
			it were [Greater resistance] to that effect’s damage.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Elemental Finesse" type="SLA"> Pick one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Forced
			VulnerabilitySLA: You can hurl a bolt of energy at an opponent in
			[Medium] range, leaving it vulnerable to further attacks. This bolt
			deals %LVL%d6 energy damage to that opponent, and inflicts
			[Vulnerability] to your element of choice on the opponent until the
			end of your next turn. A successful Reflex save halves the damage and
			negates the [Vulnerability] condition. -Elemental ResistanceEX: You
			gain [Resistance] to your chosen descriptor. When you gain your 6th
			circle of Elementalist, you gain [Immunity] to your chosen
			descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Shape the Elements" type="SLA">For each creature,
			the first time each [Round] that creature makes a save against one of
			your Elementalist abilities, if it fails, it is affected as follows:
			-Acid: [Sickened] for two [Rounds]. -Cold: [Slowed] for one
			[Round]. -Electricity: [Entangled] for two [Rounds]. -Fire:
			[Blinded] for two [Rounds] and begin [Burning]. In addition, choose
			one of the following abilities. This choice is permanent. -Elemental
			Ball: You can fire baseball-sized bits of energy... that explode!
			You may create a 20 ft radius spread originating from target square
			within [Long] range, dealing %LVL%d6 energy damage to all
			creatures in the area and pushing each of them them to the closest
			square outside of the spread that is unoccupied by an obstacle. A
			successful Reflex save halves the damage and negates the pushing
			effect. -Elemental Bolt: You may create a line with a length of
			[Medium] range originating from you, which deals %2*LVL%d4 energy damage
			per level you possess to all creatures caught in its area, and knocks
			those creatures [Prone]. A successful Reflex save halves the damage
			and negates the [Prone] condition. -Elemental Wave: You may create a
			wedge with a length of %15+5*LVL% ft originating from you
			that deals %LVL%d6 energy damage to all creatures in its area, and pushes
			them up to %5*LVL% ft, up to the outside edge of the wedge. A
			successful Reflex save halves the damage and negates the pushing
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Elemental Protection" type="SLA">Pick one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Elemental Wall: If
			there would be no creature occupying a square in the resulting area,
			you may create a line with a length of %10*LVL% ft originating
			from target square within [Medium] range, which lasts for the
			remainder of the [Encounter]. For each creature, whenever that
			creature begins its turn on a square in the line or the first time
			each [Round] that creature enters a square in the line, it is dealt %2*LVL%
			points of energy damage and gains the condition
			corresponding to your chosen descriptor, as detailed below. Acid:
			[Sickened] for 2 [Rounds]. Cold: [Slowed] for 1 [Round]. Electricity:
			[Entangled] for 2 [Rounds]. Fire: [Blinded] for 2 [Rounds] and begin
			[Burning]. -Elemental Shield: You gain the ability to shield a
			creature with your chosen element. Once per [Encounter], as a move
			action, you may grant protection to all allies within [Close] range.
			For each opponent, the first time each [Round] that opponent hits a
			creature protected by this ability with a melee attack, that opponent
			takes %LVL% energy damage. The protection
			granted by this effect lasts until the end of the [Encounter].
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Elemental Strike" type="SLA">You gain one of the
			following abilities, depending on your chosen descriptor: -Evoker’s
			Fearsome Wrath: If you channel [Fire] or [Electricity], you may
			create %LVL/2% 5 ft radius spreads, each originating from a
			target square within [Medium] range. Each spread deals %LVL%d6 energy
			damage to creatures in its radius. A successful Reflex save
			halves the damage. The spreads cannot overlap. -Conjurer’s Insidious
			Doom: If you chose [Acid] or [Cold] for this track, you may create a
			45 ft radius spread originating from target square within [Medium]
			range, which blocks line of sight, but is penetrated by [Darkvision],
			[Tremorsense], and [Ghostwise sight]. Each creature in the spread is
			dealt energy damage equal to your level and suffers a -10 ft penalty
			to its movement speed until the spread disappears, reducing its
			movement speed to a minimum of 5 ft. At the beginning of your next
			turn, each creature in the spread or that has been dealt damage from
			this ability is dealt %2*LVL% energy damage ; and
			each creature in the area suffers the following penalties until the
			spread disappears: a -20 ft penalty to its movement speed, to a
			minimum of 0 ft, and a -2 penalty on all attack rolls. On your
			following turn, each creature in the spread or that has been dealt
			damage from this ability takes %3*LVL% energy damage ;
			and each creature in the spread suffers the following
			penalties until the spread disappears: a -30 ft penalty to its
			movement speed, to a minimum of 0 ft, a -4 penalty on all attack
			rolls, and a -2 penalty on all saving throws. (Remember that
			penalties from the same ability do not stack.) On your following
			turn, the spread disappears. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Elemental Mastery" type="EX"> Whenever you deal
			damage with your chosen descriptor, any [Resistance] to that
			descriptor is calculated as if the level of its source was halved.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Elemental Rift" type="SU">You may create four 50
			ft spreads each originating from target square(s) within [Medium]
			range, each of which lasts for the rest of the [Encounter] and deals
			%LVL%d6 energy damage to creatures within its area
			when it is created and at the beginning of your turn each [Round]. A
			successful Reflex halves the damage. A given spread may overlap
			another one so long as they do not cover the exact same squares, but
			a given creature may only be dealt damage by these spreads up to 3
			times per [Round]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="airElemental" name="Air Elemental">
		<circle n="1" name="Gust" type="SLA">As either a standard action, or
			once per [Round] in place of a single attack in an attack action, you
			may unleash a small but powerful burst of wind against target
			creature within [Medium] range. The gust deals damage equal to your
			level plus your KOM, and reduces movement speed by 5 ft. This penalty
			stacks to a maximum of %5+5*CRL% ft, and lasts for %CRL% [Rounds].
			When you activate Gust by sacrificing an attack in an attack
			action (but not when you activate it as any other action), you may
			sacrifice additional attacks, up to a maximum of %LVL/5%,
			to increase damage dealt through that activation of Gust by %KOM%
			and its movement speed penalty by 5 ft for every attack you give up.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Pressure" type="SU">Pressing down on you,
			pushing down on them... As a free action, if you do not already
			have an active pressure spread, you may create a pressure spread with
			a radius of your [Melee] range originating from you that lasts and
			remains active until it is dismissed. The pressure spread moves with
			you and deals %KOM% damage to opponents within its area
			at the end of your turn, and removes any Stealth check results they
			may have. You cannot benefit from Stealth skill checks while you have
			an active pressure spread. As a free action, you may dismiss the
			pressure spread. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Fly" type="EX">You gain the Fly movement mode.
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Windstorm" type="SU">Whenever you use your Gust
			ability, you may target all opponents within [Close] range instead of
			a single creature within [Medium] range. In addition, once per
			[Round], you can activate your Gust ability as a move action.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Vacuum Wave" type="SU">Twice per [Encounter], as
			a swift action, you may move up to your movement speed. You may move
			through occupied squares and do not provoke attacks of opportunity at
			any point during this movement. Opponents in squares through which
			you move lose their next swift action.</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Ominous Wind" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			when you use your Gust ability, all opponents damaged by that ability
			are [Battered] for 3 [Rounds] and are [Blown away]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Hurricane" type="SU">Whenever you activate your
			Gust ability, you may target all opponents within [Medium] range.
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="earthElemental" name="Earth Elemental">
		<circle n="1" name="Earthspike" type="SU">The ground heeds your
			call, biting into nearby enemies. Once per [Round], as move action,
			you may create a 5 ft radius spread originating from you, dealing
			%LVL+KOM% damage to opponents within the area as a [Ground] effect.
			The radius increases to 10 ft at 5th level, and to your [Close] range at 10th level.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Earth Affinity" type="EX">You gain [Damage
			reduction] %CON%(minimum 1). In addition, moving out of a
			square of difficult terrain does not cost you extra movement.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Earthen Pull" type="SU">As a standard action,
			you may deal %2*LVL+KOM% damage  to target opponent within [Medium] range, 
			and cause the opponent to lose the [Flying] condition, 
			the Fly movement mode, and any further access the opponent may
			gain to that movement mode until the end of the [Encounter].
			This requires a successful ranged attack roll. In addition, you may choose
			to ignore any effect that would grant you [Flying]. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Core Principles" type="EX"> Pick one of the following
			abilities (this choice is permanent): -Digger’s Instincts: You dive 
			into the earth, and it parts way like water. You gain
			the Burrow movement mode. Additionally, you gain [Tremorsense] out to
			25 ft, or if you already possess [Tremorsense], you increase its
			range by 25 ft. -Mass DriverEX: A sudden, momentary rearrangement of
			gravitational fields hits your foe as hard as any hammer. You may
			make melee attacks at [Close] range. You may make melee attacks
			against [Flying] creatures when you are not [Flying], and if you hit
			a [Flying] creature with a melee attack, you may cause it to lose the
			[Flying] condition (but not the Fly movement mode). </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Striking Granite" type="SU">Once per [Round],
			when you hit an opponent with a melee attack, you may immediately
			perform the Bull Rush combat maneuver against that opponent. You do
			not need to be adjacent to this opponent or move with them and you
			can continue to push the opponent without moving. In addition, the
			opponent is knocked [Prone] at the end of the movement and loses the
			[Flying] condition if they possess it. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Gravity Well" type="SU">Once per [Encounter], as
			a standard action, you may create a spread with a radius of your
			[Close] range originating from you that pulls all opponents in its
			area to squares jacent to you, or
			as close as possible to adjacent in the event that all adjacent
			squares are occupied. If you do so, you may then create a spread with
			a radius of your [Close] range originating from you, dealing %LVL+KOM% damage
			to opponents not adjacent to you within the area as a [Ground] effect 
			and dealing %2*LVL% damage to opponents adjacent to you as a
			[Ground] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Superior Earthspike" type="EX">Earthspike can
			now be activated as a swift action. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="fireElemental" name="Fire Elemental">
		<circle n="1" name="Flame Kiss" type="SU">As a standard action, you
			may deal %KOM% energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor
			to target creature within [Medium] range, and
			cause the creature to begin [Burning]. Additionally, If you would
			take energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor, you are instead healed
			for half the damage you would have taken. This counts as a form of
			[Immunity], so you take damage as normal and are not healed by any
			effects that specifically ignore [Immunity] to [Fire]. Any
			[Resistance] or [Vulnerability] you have against the [Fire]
			descriptor is ignored if you would be healed by that damage with the
			[Fire] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Persistent Inferno" type="SU">At the beginning
			of your turn, you are healed %CRL% HPfor each creature [Burning] within [Close]
			range, up to %2*LVL% HP. Additionally, you may activate Flame Kiss as a move action. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Fire’s Embrace" type="SU">Flame Kiss now heals
			you for all the damage you would have taken instead of half the
			damage. Additionally, you may use Flame Kiss as part of another move
			action, or instead spend a single move action to hurl two separate
			Flame Kiss fireballs at two different targets. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Firewalker" type="EX">[Burning] opponents within
			your [Melee] range cannot extinguish the flames as a move action.
			Furthermore, once per move action you take, you may transport
			yourself adjacent to any creature within [Close] range that is
			[Burning]. This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity, and
			is not a [Teleport] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Unbearable Radiance" type="SU">At will, as a
			swift action, if you do not already have a heat spread, you may
			create a heat spread with a radius of your [Melee] range originating
			from you that moves with you and lasts until it is dismissed as an
			immediate action. Opponents you who begin their turn in this spread
			are dealt %LVL% energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor,
			inflicted with [Burning], and rendered [Fatigued]
			until the [Burning] condition is removed. A successful Fortitude save
			(DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the damage and the
			[Fatigued] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Sudden Inferno" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			as a standard action, you can raise an inferno from nothing, creating
			a Blaze marker in each of up to seven different target squares within
			[Medium] range, which last until the end of the [Encounter]. You can
			establish line of sight as though you occupied any square with a
			Blaze marker that you created in it. As long as you occupy a square
			with a Blaze marker that you created in it, you may enter any square
			with a Blaze marker that you created in it as though it were adjacent
			to any square you occupy with a Blaze marker you created in it and as
			though you had line of effect to it. A Blaze marker has no HP or AC,
			does not impede sight or movement, and cannot be attacked or
			targeted. At the end of each opponent’s turn, if that opponent is
			within 15 ft of a square with a Blaze marker you created in it,
			Sudden Inferno deals energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor equal
			to your character level plus your Key Offensive Modifier to that
			opponent and inflicts the [Burning] condition on that opponent.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Sirocco" type="SU">Your passing causes the air
			itself to ignite, choking the battlefield in a wake of cinders and
			devastating heat. Whenever you enter or exit a square, except as the
			result of a [Teleport] effect, you may create an Ember marker with no
			game statistics in that square that lasts until the end of the
			[Encounter]. Whenever you enter a square with an Blaze marker that
			you created in it from another square with an Blaze marker that you
			created in it, you may create an Ember token with no game statistics
			in each square that a straight line between those squares crosses
			that lasts until the end of the [Encounter]. For each creature, the
			first seven times each [Round] that creature begins its turn in or
			enters a square with one or more Ember markers created by this
			ability in it, Sirocco deals %LVL% energy damage with the [Fire] descriptor
			to that creature and inflicts the [Burning] condition on that creature. 
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="waterElemental" name="Water Elemental">
		<circle n="1" name="Agile Sea" type="EX">You may take an additional
			5 ft step each [Round], and moving out of a square of difficult
			terrain does not cost you extra movement. In addition, you gain the
			Swim movement mode. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Hungry Ocean" type="SU">Once per [Round], when
			you take an offensive action that deals damage, you may inflict 
			%2*LVL% points of [HP reduction] to a single opponent
			that would be dealt damage by that offensive action before that
			damage is dealt. You then heal HP equal to half the [HP reduction]
			inflicted by this ability. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Mist Aura" type="SU">You can wrap yourself in
			veils of mist. As a swift or move action, you may create a spread
			with a radius of your [Melee] range originating from you that lasts
			for one [Round]. This spread moves with you. Allies are [Concealed]
			while within this spread. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Viscous" type="EX"> You gain the following abilities: 
			-Surfing:You embody the crashing waves of the ocean. Once per [Round] when you
			activate Mist Aura during your turn, you may move to any unoccupied
			square within your [Close] range. This movement does not provoke an
			attack of opportunity, and ignores all obstacles. -Tidal WaveSU: You
			can transform into a wave of water. As a standard action, you may
			create a 60 ft wedge originating from you, dealing %LVL%d8 energy damage
			with the [Cold] descriptor to creatures in the area, and rendering them [Knocked down]. A
			successful Reflex save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) halves the
			damage and negates the [Knocked down] condition. You may then move to
			any unoccupied square within the wedge. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Thickening Mist" type="SU">Squares within your
			spread from your Mist Aura ability are treated as difficult terrain
			for opponents. [Flying], [Swimming], and [Burrowing] opponents in
			these squares treat this difficult terrain as if they did not have
			those conditions. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Maelstrom" type="SU">Once per [Encounter], as a
			standard action, you may create two 60 ft radius vortex spreads
			originating from target square(s) within [Medium] range, which last
			for the rest of the [Encounter] and whose squares are considered
			difficult terrain for all creatures except yourself. As a move
			action, you may move from one square within one vortex spread to an
			unoccupied square in the other vortex spread without provoking
			attacks of opportunity. An opponent who begins their turn in a square
			within a vortex spread cannot be affected by [Teleport] effects for
			one [Round] and is moved up to 30 ft toward the center of the spread
			(if this opponent began its turn in a square within both vortex
			spreads, you may choose to which vortex spread center that opponent
			is moved). A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates this effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Frozen Abyss" type="SU">The spread created from
			your Mist Aura ability now has a radius of your [Close] range, and
			may be created as a free action. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="knight" name="Knight" kom="str">
		<circle n="1" name="Deadly Blades" type="EX"> If an opponent fails a
			save against a combat maneuver you perform that deals damage, or you
			hit with an attack from a combat maneuver that does not require a
			save, that combat maneuver deals %LVL+KOM% additional damage with the
			[Precision] descriptor.
			This damage is not applied to normal attacks made while using Power
			Attack, Precise Strike, or Deadly Aim. This damage never stacks with
			itself. For instance, if a single attack is both a Trip and a Charge
			due to some special ability, it only applies once. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Valiant Challenge" type="EX">Whenever a creature
			is in your [Melee] range, it must target you if able when making
			melee attacks. The first instance of this ability to apply against a
			given creature overrides subsequent instances, so the first Knight to
			arrive is the mandatory target until he leaves, even if a second
			Knight also engages the same foe at a later time. If multiple
			instances of this ability apply at the same time against a given
			creature, that creature may choose which Knight to target. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Indefatigable" type="EX">As a move action, you
			may become [Steadied] for one [Round]. While [Steadied], you may make
			one additional attack of opportunity each [Round], and whenever you
			make an attack of opportunity, you may place yourself anywhere inside
			your [Melee] range. This does not provoke attacks of opportunity, as
			it is not movement. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="As The Six Hundred" type="EX">You may Charge
			twice as a standard action: make a Charge, and then make a second
			Charge immediately afterwards. The penalties and bonuses of these
			Charges do not stack. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Interrupt" type="EX">While [Steadied], once per
			[Encounter], you may negate any one ability activated or one spell
			cast within your [Melee] range as an immediate action. You may also
			activate this ability against ongoing effects such as [Fast healing].
			They are negated for one [Round], which still counts against their
			duration. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="On Heroes" type="EX">As part of a Charge, at any
			point in the Charge, you may move anywhere within your [Melee] range
			and make a [Bonus attack]. This movement does not provoke attacks of
			opportunity. After you make this [Bonus attack], you may continue
			your Charge in a straight line from your current location. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="New And Old" type="EX">You may use any combat
			maneuver other than Charge in place of an attack of opportunity.
			Additionally, you may now activate Interrupt twice per [Encounter].
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="mechanistSavant" name="Mechanist Savant" tam="int/cha/wis">
		<circle n="1" name="FrontLine Assemblage" type="EX">You have a
			makeshift defense network called the Assemblage. You are surrounded
			by a spread with a radius of %10*LVL% ft
			that moves with you called the Hub. The area of your Assemblage
			includes each square within this spread and each square within any
			active Generator spreads you have. The Assemblage begins each [Encounter]
			with a %TAM*3% scrap points.
			As long as the Assemblage has 1 or more scrap points, whenever
			an ally within its area or the area of an Assemblage of one of your
			allies who is present in the [Encounter] takes damage, if that ally
			has not had damage be dealt to another Assemblage this [Round], it
			may have an amount of that damage less than or equal to the number of
			scrap points the Assemblage has be dealt to the Assemblage instead.
			Whenever the Assemblage is dealt damage, it loses 1 scrap point for
			each damage dealt. At the end of each [Encounter], the Assemblage
			loses all scrap points. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="The Littlest Automatons" type="EX">You gain the
			ability to extend and repair your Assemblage by summoning tiny
			automatons. You begin each [Encounter] with %1+LVL/6% automatons
			As part of a move action, if you have at least one automaton, you may expend an
			automaton. If you do, you may create a spread you can manufacture
			originating from target square within [Medium] range, which lasts
			until the end of the [Encounter]. You can now manufacture a 10 ft
			radius Generator spread. Each Generator spread you have is active as
			long as the square it originates from is within the area of your Hub
			or the area of a Hub of any creature to whom you are an ally and who
			is present in the [Encounter]. Each Hunger spread you create is
			active as long as the square it originates from is within the area of
			your Assemblage or the area of an Assemblage of any creature to whom
			you are an ally and who is present in the [Encounter]. At the end of
			your turn, for each active Generator spread you have, your Assemblage
			gains a number of scrap points equal to %TAM% plus the number of
			other active Generator spreads you have. As a free action, you may
			end one Generator or Hunger spread you have. If you do, you gain one
			automaton. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Trust in Steam" type="EX">Your automatons grant
			you a mechanical detection network. You gain [Tremorsense] out to
			each square within your Assemblage. </circle>
		<circle n="4"
			name="The Consuming Spark: You gain the following abilities: -The Teeth Grind Faster"
			type="EX">Your automatons take on a more sinister design. You can now
			manufacture a 35 ft radius Hunger spread. Additionally, as a swift
			action, if you have at least one automaton, you may expend an
			automaton. If you do, you may create a spread you can manufacture
			originating from target square within [Medium] range, which lasts
			until the end of the [Encounter]. -The FeedSU: At the end of your
			turn, each active Hunger spread you created deals %2*TAM% damage
			to each opponent within its area. If one or more
			opponents were dealt damage this way, your Assemblage gains %TAM% scrap points.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5"
			name="Giants in Iron" type="EX">You gain the following abilities: -Refit:
			As an immediate action, any ally within your Assemblage can
			choose an active Generator or Hunger spread you created. If that
			ally does, that ally may create a 45 ft radius Decimation spread
			originating from target square of that ally’s choice within your
			[Medium] range of the square from which the chosen spread originates,
			then you end the chosen spread and gain one automaton. -OverclockSU:
			Whenever an ally creates a Decimation spread, if that spread did not
			end, that spread deals %LVL% damage to each opponent within its area.
			For each opponent in that spread, as a [Dispelling] effect,
			the ally that created it ends up to one effect of that its choice
			created by a spell or spell-like ability that has
			a duration and that originates from that opponent or targeted that
			opponent. End that spread. (You are your own ally. )</circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Scrapheap Hero" type="EX">You gain the following abilities: 
			-Grist Central: Your armor is augmented with strange devices of your own
			crafting. Your armor’s item bonus to AC is increased by 2. At the
			beginning of each [Encounter], you may create a spread you can
			manufacture originating from yourself that moves with you and lasts
			until the end of the [Encounter]. -I Meant to Do That!SU: Once per
			[Round], as an immediate action, you may create a 45 ft radius
			Decimation spread originating from target square within [Medium]
			range. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="To Bend Steel" type="EX">Kneel before the power of metal! 
			You gain the following abilities: -One Man’s Trash...:
			At the end of your turn, for each active Generator spread you
			have, your Assemblage gains four scrap points. At the beginning of
			your turn, you may end any number of Hunger spreads you have that do
			not move with you. For each spread you end this way, choose a target
			square within a distance equal to your movement speed of the square
			from which that spread originates. You create a Hunger spread
			originating from the chosen square. -Junk BondSU: Whenever an
			opponent exits an active Hunger spread you created, that spread deals
			%2*TAM% damage to that opponent. If an opponent was
			dealt damage this way, your Assemblage gains %TAM% scrap points.
			-Not Under WarrantySU: As an immediate action, any ally within your 
			Assemblage can choose two active Generator or Hunger spreads you created.
			If that ally does, that ally may create two 45 ft radius Decimation
			spreads each originating from a target square of that ally’s choice within
			your [Medium] range of the square rom which a different one of the chosen
			spreads originates, then you end the chosen spreads and gain two automatons. 
			-That Too!SU: Once per [Round], as an immediate action, you may create two 45 ft radius
			Decimation spreads each originating from a target square within
			[Medium] range. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="necromancer" name="Necromancer" tam="spell">
		<circle n="1" name="Speak with Dead" type="SU">Once per [Scene], you can grant the
			semblance of life and intellect to a corpse for half an hour, allowing
			it to answer several questions that you put to it. You may ask one
			question per two levels you possess. Unasked questions are wasted if
			the duration expires. The corpse is compelled to answer each question
			truthfully, although the corpse’s knowledge is limited to what the
			creature knew during life, including the languages it spoke (if any),
			and the creature is only compelled to answer the explicit question
			asked. Furthermore, you can only interrogate a corpse that is
			reasonably intact (at least head and throat) and cannot interrogate a
			corpse that has been subject to Speak With Dead in the previous week.
			If the corpse is already animated, such as an [Undead] creature, you
			cannot interrogate it with this ability.
		</circle>
		<circle n="1" name="Apprentice of Darkness" type="SLA">You can choose
			to damage [Undead] creatures with [Negative] effects as if they were
			not [Undead], and whenever one of your abilities would affect a
			creature with [Immunity] to [Negative] effects, you may choose to
			treat their [Immunity] as if it were [Greater resistance] to damage
			with the [Negative] descriptor. Additionally, choose one of the
			following abilities. This choice is permanent. When you gain your 4th
			Circle of the Necromancer track, you can activate your chosen ability
			as part of a standard action to activate any spell-like ability from
			the Necromancer track (including your chosen ability). -Cause Fear:
			As a move action, you may force an opponent within [Close] range to
			become [Shaken] for 2 [Rounds]. A successful Will save negates the
			[Shaken] condition. This is a [Fear], [Mind-affecting] ability. »
			Chill Touch: You may deal %LVL%d4 + %KOM% damage
			to an opponent within [Melee] range. This does not
			provoke attacks of opportunity, but it requires a successful melee
			attack roll. This is a [Negative] ability. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Whispers of the Afterlife" type="SU">Choose one
			of the following abilities (this choice is permanent): -False Life:
			As a swift action, you can give yourself %LVL% temporary HP.
			These temporary HP disappear at the end of the [Scene]. -Crippling
			Aura: You can summon the negative energy that courses through the
			world to wrack enemies around you with pain and limit their mobility.
			Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you may create a spread with
			a radius of your [Close] range originating from you that moves with
			you and lasts until the end of the [Encounter]. Whenever an opponent
			ends its turn in a square within the spread, it takes a -10 ft
			penalty to its movement speed on its next turn. This is a [Negative]
			ability. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Blight From the Beyond" type="SLA">Pick one of
			the following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Vampiric Touch:
			Once per [Encounter], you may deal %LVL%d8 damage to an opponent 
			within [Melee] range. This does not provoke
			attacks of opportunity, but it requires a successful melee attack
			roll. You heal HP equal to half of the damage dealt, and if this
			would heal you above your maximum HP, you add any excess healing as
			temporary HP that last until the end of the [Encounter]. This is a
			[Negative] ability. -Blindness: As a standard action, you may cause
			target creature within [Close] range to become [Blinded] for 2
			[Rounds]. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Ebb and Flow" type="SLA">Choose one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Enervation: Once
			per [Encounter], you may inflict the [Energy drained] condition 1d4
			times on an opponent within [Medium] range. This requires a
			successful ranged attack roll. This is a [Negative] ability. »
			Enervating Strike: Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you can
			empower your melee attacks with negative energy; each time you hit an
			opponent with a melee attack this [Round], you inflict [Energy
			drained] on the hit opponent. This is a [Negative] ability. »
			Protection from Death: Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you
			may grant a single target within [Close] range [Immunity] to [Death]
			effects and all conditions and nondamaging effects inflicted by
			abilities with the [Negative] descriptor, and [Greater resistance] to
			all damage dealt by abilities with the [Negative] descriptor. This
			effect lasts for the [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Dread Lord" type="SLA">Choose one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Slay Living: Once
			per [Encounter], you can deal %6*LVL% damage to a target within
			[Close] range and apply the [Battered] condition to that target. A
			successful Fortitude save halves the damage and prevents the damage
			from reducing the target below 1 hit point. This is a [Negative],
			[Death] ability. -Retributive Armor: Once per [Encounter] as a move
			action, you can call up clouds of negative energy that surround your
			person and lash out at your foes. For the remainder of the
			[Encounter], for each opponent, the first time each [Round] that
			opponent hits you with an attack while within [Close] range, that
			opponent is [Shaken] for 1 [Round] and dealt 1 point of damage per
			level. This is a [Negative] ability. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Wave of Terror" type="SLA">You can release a huge
			wave of negative energy. Once per [Encounter], you may create a wedge
			with a length of %5*LVL% ft originating from you,
			which deals %LVL%d6 damage and inflicts the
			[Exhausted] and [Frightened] conditions to all opponents in its area.
			A successful Fortitude save leaves the opponents [Fatigued] and
			[Shaken] instead of [Exhausted] and [Frightened]. This is a
			[Negative], [Fear], [Mind-affecting] ability. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Wail of the Banshee" type="SLA">You can release a
			horrible shriek, rending the air and destroying your enemies
			completely. Once per [Encounter], you may create a spread with a
			radius equal to your [Medium] range originating from you, dealing %6*LVL%
			damage and applying the [Battered] condition to all
			opponents within [Medium] range. A successful Fortitude save halves
			the damage. This is a [Negative], [Death] ability. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="runesongScholar" name="Runesong Scholar" tam="int/wis/cha">
		<circle n="1" name="Semantics" type="SU">You gain access to the
			following abilities, which may be activated as a swift action, at
			will : -Know Truenames: You have learned how to glean the true name
			of another, even if they do not know it themselves. At will, you may
			force a creature within [Close] range to surrender the knowledge of
			its true name. A successful Will save negates this effect, and gives
			the creature [Immunity] to this ability for the remainder of the
			[Scene]. -Heed My Words: You can speak a true name to make its owner
			painfully aware of your words. The creature hears the next sentence
			you speak regardless of distance, and if it is within [Extreme] range
			it is [Shaken] for 1 [Round] at your option. It is a [Fear],
			[Mind-affecting] ability if you choose to make your target [Shaken].
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Trace the Lines" type="SU">You gain access to
			the following abilities, which may be activated as a swift action, at
			will : -Affirmation of Existence: You can speak a creature’s true
			name that you know to reveal the creature’s location. This makes you
			and your allies aware of the creature’s cardinal direction if it is
			within [Extreme] range, or precise location if within [Medium] range,
			and this causes the creature to be [Revealed] for one [Round]. You do
			not need line of sight or effect to the creature to activate this
			ability. -Denial of Existence: You may intentionally mangle one true
			name you know. If the true name’s owner is within [Medium] range, he
			takes %2*TAM% damage.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Will of the Elements" type="SU">You gain access
			to the following abilities: -Song Shield: Through practice in the
			tongue from which all things were formed, you gain an unspoken bond
			with the base elements. At the beginning of your turn, you gain a
			Song Shield that grants [Lesser resistance] against the next source
			of energy damage you suffer. Song Shields accumulate during an
			[Encounter] and stack with one another, but each time you are dealt
			energy damage, a single Song Shield dissipates. All Song Shields
			dissipate at the end of each [Encounter]. -Moniker: You may not know
			the true name of every blade of grass, but you can craft temporary
			“nicknames” for them. Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you
			may give a Moniker to %LVL% creatures within [Close] range.
			The Moniker expires at the end of the [Encounter]. A
			Moniker can be used in the place of a proper true name. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="The Earth Calls" type="SU">You can send the
			earth up to meet someone, like a particularly ungentlemanly caller.
			At will, you may cause a creature within [Close] range whose true
			name you know to take damage equal to your character level and be
			[Slowed] for two [Rounds]. A successful Reflex save negates the
			[Slowed] condition. You cannot choose the same target for The Earth
			Calls more than once per [Encounter]. You do not need line of sight
			or effect to the creature to activate this ability. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Unbreakable Oath" type="SU">The first time each
			[Encounter] that a given creature is targeted by one of your Runesong
			Abilities that is not Know Truenames or Moniker, that creature
			becomes [Oathsworn] to you for the rest of the [Encounter]. While the
			creature is [Oathsworn] to you, if it would take an offensive action
			that targets you, that action is not taken. A successful Will save
			allows the creature to take the action; an unsuccessful Will save
			renders the creature no longer [Oathsworn] to you. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Abjure" type="SU">For a brief moment, you can
			convince the universe that a creature doesn’t exist. If you know the
			true name of target creature within [Medium] range and if that
			creature had not been targeted by this ability this [Encounter], as a
			swift action you may render the creature [Ethereal] for one [Round] .
			A successful Will save negates this effect. While a creature is
			[Ethereal] as a result of this ability, line of sight is blocked
			between the creature and other creatures besides you, and line of
			effect is blocked between the creature and any other creature’s
			attack, ability, or effect. You do not need line of sight or effect
			to the creature to use this ability. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Unname" type="SU">You gain the ultimate power
			over true names – the knowledge of their destruction. At will, as a
			standard action, you can cause a creature within [Close] range whose
			true name you know to suffer [HP reduction] equal to half of their
			maximum hit points. A successful Will save negates this effect. You
			do not need line of sight or effect to the creature to activate this
			ability</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="trueMage" name="True Mage" tam="spell">
		<circle n="1" name="Kingship" type="EX">You may bestow ritual
			blessings upon allies at the beginning of a [Scene]. Until
			discharged, each of these abilities lasts for the duration of the
			[Scene]. A creature may only benefit from one ritual blessing at a
			time. You have access to the following ritual blessings, though each
			must be placed only once per [Scene] and on a different ally: »
			Sword: Whenever an ally who possesses this ritual blessing hits an
			opponent with an attack, that opponent takes a -10 ft penalty to
			their movement speed until the end of the [Encounter]. In addition,
			as a free action, after hitting an opponent with an attack, that ally
			may discharge this ritual blessing to inflict a penalty equal to the
			number of circles of True Mage you possess to the AC of one opponent
			within [Close] range. This penalty lasts until the end of the
			[Encounter]. -Shield: For each opponent, the first time each [Round]
			that opponent’s melee attack hits an ally possessing this ability,
			that opponent takes 1 point of damage per level of the ally. In
			addition, as a free action, that ally may discharge this ritual
			blessing to create a spread with a radius of that ally’s [Close]
			originating from that ally, dealing damage equal to your TAM + your
			level to all opponents in the area. -Sceptre: The ally who possesses
			this ability has the power to speak words which hold greater weight
			to other creatures. That ally receives a +2 bonus to a social skill
			of their choice, or to Awareness. When attempting to reason with a
			hostile creature, the ally may discharge this ability as a free
			action to gain a token for the social encounter. </circle>
		<circle n="2"
			name="Foundation: Once per [Scene], as a standard action, you gain one of the following abilities until the end of the [Scene]: -Theurgic Secret"
			type="EX"> Choose a single spell you know, of any circle lower than the
			highest circle of spells you can cast. You may cast this spell once
			per [Encounter] without expending a spell slot. -Alchemical
			MysteriesSU: As a move action, if you possess the Combat Alchemist
			track, you may expend a consumable to convert one of your Potions or
			Poisons into a consumable with effects identical to that Brew. This
			consumable expires at the end of the [Scene]. -Goetic StrengthEX:
			Choose either spell-like or supernatural abilities. Calculate all
			leveldependent variables, such as range, damage, and DCs, for
			abilities of the chosen type you possess as if you were two levels
			higher. -Arcane PreparationSU: Once per [Scene], after spending no
			actions for 5 minutes, you may create a spread with a radius of your
			[Close] range originating from you that lasts for the rest of the
			[Scene]. If any creature enters a square within this spread, the
			glyph alerts you (a harmless mental jolt sufficient to wake you from
			sleep) and conveys an image of the creature, along with a vague sense
			of the creature’s general intent. When you create the spread, you can
			choose to direct it to ignore creatures fitting a certain description
			(such as “small animals and insects”), as well as yourself and/or
			anyone inside the spread when it is created. You can also direct the
			spread to repel creatures fitting a certain description no more
			complex than race and a range of height and weight. A creature under
			that description is unable to enter a square within the spread. A
			successful Will save (DC 10 + ½ your level + your TAM) allows the
			creature to enter a square within the spread for the rest of the
			[Scene]. Finally, creatures outside the spread cannot establish line
			of sight to any creature within the spread from your [Long] range or
			farther. Creatures outside your [Medium] range from the spread also
			cannot establish line of sight to any creature within the spread
			unless they are able to ignore [Figment] or [Glamer] effects. Taking
			an offensive action against an opponent while inside a square
			124within the spread allows any creature to establish line of sight
			as normal to creatures within the spread for the rest of the [Scene].
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Splendor" type="SU"> You gain access to three
			broader rituals which take a hundred [Rounds] to cast each. Out of
			combat, this is roughly equivalent to ten minutes. -Seal: You create
			a Splendorous seal over a door or object, stopping it from being
			opened without two [Rounds] of concerted effort. You may only have
			one Seal in existence for each circle of True Mage you have acquired,
			and only one active on a given door or object. These seals function
			while you are within 750 ft, and 5 minutes after you leave that
			radius. You may open a seal or reseal it at anytime. As a swift
			action, you may discharge a seal in order to deal damage equal to
			your character level plus your Key Offensive Modifier to all
			opponents within 20 ft of the seal. -Trickery: You create a Rune of
			Trickery on an ally. You may only have one Rune in existence for each
			circle of True Mage you have acquired, and only one active on a given
			ally. While a Rune of Trickery is on an ally, that ally may alter
			their appearance at will. A Perception check (DC 10 + ½ your
			character level + your KAM) makes an observer aware of the deception.
			This Rune lasts for the duration of the [Quest]. The ally may
			discharge this Rune as a move action or part of a move action to
			[Teleport] to a destination point within [Close] range, and become
			[Invisible] for two [Rounds]. -Majesty: You create a symbol of
			Majesty on an ally. You may only have a one Symbol in existence for
			each circle of True Mage you have acquired, and only one active on a
			given ally. This symbol lasts for the duration of the [Quest]. An
			affected ally gains a 10 ft bonus to their [Melee] range, and
			opponents hit by their melee attacks begin [Burning]. As a move
			action, the ally may discharge the symbol to cause all opponents
			within the ally’s improved [Melee] range to be [Blown away] and begin
			[Burning]. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Eternity" type="EX">Your control over the
			Splendor Rituals increases. You may now prepare these rituals in
			advance on some form of item, like a card or a scroll, that you can
			then use for the ritual. A ritual prepared in this fashion can be
			used as a swift action, as long as the subject is within [Melee]
			range. No two True Mages may use each other’s rituals prepared this
			way, and where applicable, cards count against the total number of
			instances you may have active for a given ritual. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Severity" type="SU">At the start of each
			[Scene], you possess one of the following abilities of your choice
			until the end of the [Scene]: -Circle of Ether: Your ability to bind
			magic into physical forms takes on a startling new aspect. At the
			start of this [Scene], you gain two consumables: a Rusted Ring and
			Gloss Armor. If they have not been used by the end of the [Scene],
			these two consumables crumble into dust, as do any consumables you
			have created with them using the Alchemical Mysteries ability. »
			Binding of The Seventh: Once per [Scene], after spending no actions
			for 5 minutes, you may create a shackle spread with a radius of your
			[Close] range originating from 125 Chapter VI: Additional
			Trackstarget adjacent square, which remains dormant until activated
			or until you create a new shackle spread with this ability. If you
			create a new shackle spread, this shackle spread disappears. As a
			standard action, you may activate the shackle spread. Creatures
			within an activated shackle spread cannot be affected by [Teleport]
			effects (actions taken on using such [Teleport] effects are still
			spent), and opponents within an activated shackle spread are
			inflicted with the [Slowed] condition for as long as they are within
			the shackle spread. A successful Will save (DC 10 + ½ your level +
			your TAM) causes a creature to become [Entangled] instead of [Slowed]
			while inside the shackle spread. Once activated, the shackle spread
			lasts for ten [Rounds] and then disappears. </circle>
		<circle n="6"
			name="Understanding: As you master the ancient arts of the mage, you can combine your powers in unusual ways. You may choose one of the following abilities; this choice is permanent, unless your GM is unusually forgiving: -Dual Focus"
			type="EX">You learn to split your arcane focus between two constant
			effects. You may have two instances of your Foundation ability active
			simultaneously, and their effects stack if they provide the same
			ability. -Glyph of CallingSU: You can craft linked magic circles,
			enabling instant travel between their locations. Once per [Scene],
			with two hours’ effort, you can create a teleportation circle with a
			10-ft radius linked to any other teleportation circle within a
			distance of 100 miles per level you possess. Any creature that enters
			a linked teleportation circle’s space is immediately transported to
			the teleportation circle to which it is linked, along with up to 250
			pounds of equipment. The circle is permanent but can be destroyed
			either by a 7thcircle [Dispelling] effect or by ten minutes’ physical
			labor. This is a [Teleport] and [Warp] effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Crown" type="EX">At the beginning of each
			[Scene], you possess one of the following abilities of your choice
			until the end of the [Scene]. -Ars Arcana: If you have the Combat
			Alchemist track, you may reduce the transmutation point cost of all
			your abilities by one, to a minimum of one point. -Magna Anima: At
			the beginning of each [Scene], pick a single spell that you know of a
			circle lower than your highest spell circle with a casting time of “1
			standard action”. Once per [Encounter], as a swift action, you may
			cast that spell without expending a spell slot. In addition, once per
			[Encounter], as a swift action, if you possess the Theurgic Secret
			ability this [Scene] and your chosen spell from that ability has a
			casting time of “1 standard action”, you may cast that chosen spell
			without expending a spell slot. -Ars Goetia: Once per [Scene], you
			may activate any two spell-like abilities you possess with a casting
			time of a standard action or a swift action with a single standard
			action. You can choose the order in which the abilities take effect.
			This action counts against any limits for using those spell-like
			abilities, and you may not activate a spell-like ability that has no
			remaining uses or otherwise could not normally be activated. 126 »
			Magna Mutatio: Once per [Scene], you may transform any consumable
			into any other consumable of the same tier. This takes one [Round] of
			effort. 
		</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="vigilante" name="Vigilante">
		<circle n="1" name="Vigilante Armor" type="EX">With a dramatic
			gesture and shouted command, a suit of incredible armor snaps into
			existence and covers your body. This provides a +2 item bonus to
			Athletics, and is a Lesser item of your design with enchantments as
			normal for magic armor of its tier (see Chapter XIII), but does not
			count against your normal limit of attuned magic items. When you gain
			your 4th circle in Vigilante, redesign this armor as a Greater item,
			and when you gain your 6th circle, redesign it as a Relic. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Brutal Kick" type="EX">As a standard action, you
			may move up to your movement speed, or your mount’s movement speed if
			you are mounted, without provoking attacks of opportunity, and then
			make a melee attack against an opponent in your [Melee] range. This
			attack deals %LVL% additional damage. If you’re not
			[Burrowing], [Flying], [Swimming], or [Soaring], you can target a
			[Flying] creature with this attack. If you’re [Flying] but not
			[Burrowing], [Swimming], or [Soaring], you can target a creature that
			isn’t [Burrowing], [Flying], [Swimming], or [Soaring] with this
			attack. You can choose to treat your Unarmed Strike natural weapon as
			a [Brutal 2], [Magnum] weapon for purposes of this attack. At 10th
			level, you can make 2 of these attacks after moving this way, and the
			additional damage for each attack increases to %2*LVL%. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Signature Ride" type="EX"> If you do not already
			have a Personal Mount, as a move action, you may summon or dismiss a
			mysterious contraption, called your Signature Ride. This is a special
			mount. You may only have one Signature Ride, which you may treat as
			your Personal Mount. Only you can be its rider, and you can become
			and remain its rider during combat even if you do not have the Ride
			skill trained. You cannot become its passenger. Whenever you summon
			it, it appears in an unoccupied space adjacent to yours. Whenever you
			dismiss it, it disappears; if you are its rider, you cease to be its
			rider. As a free action, if you are adjacent to your Signature Ride
			or are in a square it occupies, you may become the rider of your
			Signature Ride without provoking attacks of opportunity. It has a
			movement speed equal to your movement speed + 15 ft, the Fly movement
			mode, and a space equal in size and shape to your own. While you are
			the rider of your Signature Ride, you gain a 20% [Miss chance]
			against all attacks during any [Round] in which you move at least 20
			ft. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Unnatural Resilience" type="EX">Through esoteric
			means, you are simply tougher and more enduring than any life ought
			to be. If you make a successful Fortitude save against an effect that would normally have a
			lesser effect on a successful save (such as a spell with a save of
			“Fortitude half ”), you instead ignore the effect entirely. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Vigilante’s Courage" type="EX">You have
			[Immunity] to [Fear] and gain a +2 bonus to initiative checks, due to
			your prodigious courage. Twice per [Round], whenever this ability
			negates an effect, or you successfully make a Fortitude save, you may
			make a Brutal Kick against the opponent that created the effect, as
			long as your Brutal Kick ability could bring you within your [Melee]
			range of that opponent. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Finishing Move" type="EX"> You learn to
			devastate your enemies, leaving you refreshed for your next
			challenger. Once per [Encounter], as a standard action, you may move
			up to your movement speed, or your mount’s movement speed if you are
			mounted, without provoking attacks of opportunity, and then make a
			melee attack against an opponent in your [Melee] range. This attack
			deals %5*LVL% additional damage, and you gain
			temporary HP equal to the damage dealt by this attack. You can choose
			to treat your Unarmed Strike natural weapon as a [Brutal 2], [Magnum]
			weapon for purposes of this attack. If you’re not [Burrowing],
			[Flying], [Swimming], or [Soaring], you can target a [Flying]
			creature with this attack. If you’re [Flying] but not [Burrowing],
			[Swimming], or [Soaring], you can target a creature that isn’t
			[Burrowing], [Flying], [Swimming], or [Soaring] with this attack.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Unbeaten" type="EX">Once per [Encounter], as a
			move action, you can heal all damage, setting your current hit point
			total to your maximum HP. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="celestial" name="Celestial">
		<circle n="1" name="Divine Radiance" type="SU">At will, as a free
			action, if you do not already have a radiant spread, you may create a
			radiant spread with a radius of your [Close] originating from you
			that moves with you and lasts until dismissed as a swift action. This
			spread causes opponents in it to lose the [Covered] condition and be
			[Revealed]. Any opponent who leaves the spread is [Revealed] for one
			[Round] and cannot benefit from the [Covered] condition for one
			[Round]. As a swift action, you may increase the light’s brightness
			momentarily, leaving all opponents within the radiant spread
			[Dazzled] for 5 [Rounds]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+WIS%)
			reduces the duration of the [Dazzled] condition to 1 [Round]. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Sway the Heavens" type="EX">Your attacks awe
			opponents with their wondrous grace. %CRL-1% times per [Round], if you hit an
			opponent that has been [Revealed] by your Divine Radiance with an
			attack, you may cause that opponent to be unable to make attacks of
			opportunity for one [Round]. This does not require an action.</circle>
		<circle n="3"
			name="Path to Glory" type="EX">You gain one of the following abilities:
			-Angelic Wings You gain a pair of wings and the Fly movement mode.
			-Prophetic VisionsSU: Brief glimpses into the future offer you keen
			insight into battle. Once per [Round], when you activate Divine
			Radiance as a swift action, you may gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls
			or Armor Class until the beginning of your next turn. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Benediction" type="SU">You gain one of the
			following abilities: -Strength of Faith: Twice per [Encounter], you
			can activate the Divine Radiance ability as an immediate action, and
			replace the Armor Class or one saving throw bonus of an ally within
			the range of your Divine Radiance with your own for one [Round]. When
			you do so, you may benefit from other abilities you possess that
			trigger when you activate Divine Radiance as a swift action. -Aura
			of Vitality: You gain [Immunity] to the [Blinded] condition. In
			addition, twice per [Encounter], when you activate Divine Radiance as
			a swift action, you may grant all allies within the range of your
			Divine Radiance %2*LVL% temporary HP. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Harmonious Scales" type="SLA">You gain one of the
			following abilities: -Purifying Flame: Twice per [Encounter], as a
			standard action, you may use sunburst, as the spell. The DC to resist
			it is %10+LVL/2+WIS%. -Cleansing Light:
			Twice per [Encounter], as a standard action, you may use heal, as the
			spell. The DC to resist it is %10+LVL/2+WIS%. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Righteous Wrath" type="EX">You gain one of the
			following abilities: -Strike Senseless: The first time you hit an
			opponent with an attack each [Round], that opponent is [Blinded] and
			[Deafened] for 1 [Round]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+WIS%
			negates the [Blinded] and [Deafened]
			conditions. -That Hideous Strength: Once per [Round], when you make
			an attack, you may force all enemies within the area of your Divine
			Radiance to make a Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+WIS%)
			or be [Battered] for 2 [Rounds]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Divine Mercy" type="SU">Once per [Encounter],
			when you activate Divine Radiance as a swift action, you call down a
			shield of blistering light which grants a single ally within [Long]
			range [Immunity] to damage for a single [Round]. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="demon" name="Demon">
		<circle n="1" name="Demonic Traits" type="EX">Select one Interaction
			skill (Bluff, Diplomacy, Intimidate, or Perception). You gain a +3
			bonus on all checks with that skill. A demon also has the following
			natural weapon: -Demon Claws – Melee, range [Melee], [Brutal 2],
			[Devastating]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Demon Magic" type="SLA">Once per [Encounter], as
			a standard action, you may use either darkness or see invisibility,
			as the spells. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Abominable Essence" type="EX">
			Select one of the following abilities (this choice is permanent): 
			-Fell Flight: You gain wings and the Fly movement mode. -Apocalyptic
			VisionsSU: Brief glimpses into the future offer you keen insights
			into battle. Once per [Round], as a swift action, you may gain a +3
			bonus to attack rolls or to Armor Class for one [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Thick Skinned" type="EX">You gain a +%CRL% item
			bonus to your Armor Class, and [Lesser resistance] to physical damage.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5"
			name="Vessel of Entropy" type="SU">Select one of the following abilities (this choice is permanent):
			-Shield of Chaos: You gain a 20% [Miss chance], and your [Lesser resistance] to
			physical damage improves to [Resistance] to physical damage. 
			-Chaos HammerSLA: Twice per [Encounter], as a standard action, you may deal
			%LVL%d8 damage inflict [Energy drained] to all opponents within
			[Close] range. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			halves the damage and negates the [Energy drained] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Cruel Reality" type="SU">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Bonded by Blood:
			You gain the ability to sense how close to death creatures are. You
			know the maximum and current HP of every creature within [Medium]
			range to which you have line of sight. In addition, as a swift
			action, you can form a horrifying bond with a creature within
			[Medium] range that splits all damage you take equally with that
			creature until the end of the [Encounter]. (You can damage yourself
			to damage the bonded creature. ) [Damage reduction] and [Resistance]
			do not apply to damage that creature takes from this ability. As a
			move action, that creature may make a Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			to sever this bond. A creature
			may only have one such bond at a time. -Aura of Insanity: Once per
			[Round], as a free action, you may create spread with a radius of
			your [Close] range originating from you, which renders all opponents
			within the area [Confused] for one [Round]. A successful Will save
			(DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Confused] condition.
			Each opponent may only be affected by this ability once per
			[Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Aura of Death" type="SU">Everything around you
			seems to die faster than it otherwise should. At the start of each of
			your turns, all opponents in [Medium] range gain the [Bleeding]
			condition, all opponents in [Close] range gain the [Battered]
			condition for one [Round], and whenever you hit an opponent with an
			attack in [Melee] range, that attack deals %KOM*2% additional damage. 
			A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Battered]
			condition. (These effects are cumulative. For instance, a creature in your [Melee]
			range suffers all three effects. )</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="dragon" name="Dragon">
		<circle n="1" name="Agility" type="EX"> You gain the Fly movement
			mode. You also gain the following natural weapon: -Dragon Claws –
			Melee, range [Melee], [Brutal 3]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Vitality" type="EX">Your maximum HP increases by %CRL*LVL%.</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="True Dragon" type="EX">This marks your
			transition from your previous form to the dragon you were meant to
			be. Your scales have formed a protective coat, which can be improved
			with enchantments (see Chapter XIII) as if it were armor, though it
			is not treated as armor for any other purpose. This coat grants you a
			+3 item bonus to AC, which improves by +1 if it is enchanted as a
			Lesser Item, or +2 if it is enchanted as a Greater Item, or +3 if it
			is enchanted as a Relic, or +4 if it is enchanted as an Artifact. The
			Masterwork enchantment can never be applied to your scales. In
			addition, whenever you hit with an attack using your Dragon Claws,
			you are healed for half the damage you dealt on that attack, up to
			%LVL% HP. Abilities or effects that would increase this
			ability’s healing do so only once per [Round]. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Dignity" type="EX">All conditions and [Binding]
			effects affecting you have their durations reduced by one [Round], to
			a minimum of 1 [Round]. If a condition would normally persist for an
			[Encounter], it instead lasts eight [Rounds] or until the [Encounter]
			ends, whichever occurs first. If a condition would normally persist
			for a [Scene], it instead lasts for the [Encounter]. If a condition
			would normally persist for a [Quest], it instead lasts for the
			[Scene]. Permanent conditions are unaltered. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Endurance" type="EX">Fatal damage you are
			subjected to takes a full [Round] to kill or incapacitate you. During
			that [Round], you may be healed. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Power" type="EX"> Twice per [Encounter], as a
			swift action, you may let loose a horrible challenge. Opponents
			within [Close] range are [Deafened] for one [Round], and they must
			use their standard and move actions to either flee or approach you
			(using standard actions to Run and move actions to move away), or
			target you with offensive actions for one [Round]. A successful Will
			save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates this effect. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Great Wyrm" type="EX">You have grown in power,
			transcending the mortality of lesser beings. Once per [Scene],
			whenever you die or are rendered [Unconscious], you are revived at
			the beginning of the next [Round] with full HP. You can delay your
			revival or choose not to return at all. If you die more than once
			during a [Scene], you may come back to life at the beginning of the
			next [Quest].</circle>
	</track>
	<track id="sentientConstruct" name="Sentient Construct">
		<circle n="1" name="Sturdy Frame" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Hard to Break: Once
			per [Encounter], if you make a successful Fortitude or Will save
			against an effect that would normally have a lesser effect on a
			successful save (such as a spell with a save of “Fortitude half ”),
			you instead ignore the effect entirely. -Harder, Better, Faster,
			Stronger: You gain a +%CRL% bonus to all damage,
			and a %5*CRL/2% ft bonus to your movement speed. 
			You also gain a +2 bonus to saves against combat maneuvers. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Built to Last" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Nanites: You gain
			[Fast healing] %KDM%. -Heavy Metal:
			As a standard action, you deal %LVL+KOM% damage to every opponent in [Melee] range.
			Opponents dealt damage by this ability are [Knocked down]. A
			successful Reflex save (DC  %10+LVL/2+KOM%) egates being [Knocked down]. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Onboard Radar" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Sensor Suite: Your
			advanced senses enable you to penetrate illusions that would fool
			organic creatures. You gain [Immunity] to effects with the [Figment]
			descriptor. You also gain [Tremorsense] out to [Close] range and
			[Blindsight] out to [Melee] range. -Targeting System: You gain
			[Tremorsense] out to [Close] range. Whenever you use [Tremorsense] to
			image the area (see Chapter IX), you gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls
			against any opponent within your [Tremorsense] that [Round], and
			whenever you deal damage with an attack to an opponent within your
			[Tremorsense] that [Round], you deal %CRL%d4 additional damage with the
			[Precision] descriptor. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Defensive Matrix" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Spell Disruption:
			You gain [Resistance] to energy and magic damage. -Active
			Stabilizers: You gain [Resistance] to physical damage. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Auxiliary Systems" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Precise Logic: You
			gain [Immunity] to effects with the [Mind-affecting] descriptor. »
			Suppressive Fire: As a move action, you may create a line with a
			length of your [Medium] range originating from you that deals 2d4 x %KOM%
			damage to creatures within the area and knocks them [Prone]. 
			A successful Reflex save (DC  %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Prone] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Upgraded Chassis" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Iron Constitution:
			You gain [Immunity] to the [Bleeding], [Sickened], and [Nauseated]
			conditions. -Charged Attack: Once
			per [Round], as a swift action, you may charge up energy. Whenever
			you do so, you gain a +%KOM% bonus to damage you deal with attacks or
			offensive actions for one [Round]. All damage you
			deal with attacks or offensive actions during that [Round] also
			ignores %LVL/2% points of [Damage reduction] and [Resistance], 
			and may inflict the [Burning] and [Bleeding] conditions at your choice. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="State of the Art" type="EX">Select one of the
			following abilities (this choice is permanent): -Kinetic
			Bombardment: As a standard action, you may pick one square within
			[Medium] range. You deal 15d6 damage to all creatures within your
			[Close] range from that square. Those creatures lose [Flying] and the
			the Fly movement mode for two [Rounds]. In addition, creatures dealt
			damage by this ability are [Blown away] in a direction of your
			choice. A successful Fortitude save (DC  %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates being [Blown away]. -Big Finish: Three times per [Encounter],
			as a move action, the next time you hit an opponent with an attack, 
			that attack deals %4*LVL% additional fury damage and inflicts the [Battered]
			condition until the end of the [Encounter], and the [Slowed] condition
			for two [Rounds]. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) 
			halves the additional damage and negates the [Slowed] condition.
			This is a [Death] effect. </circle>
	</track>
	<track bindId="undead" id="ghoul" name="Ghoul">
		<circle n="1" name="Horrible Bite" type="SU">You draw strength from
			the flesh of sentient creatures. Once per [Round], when you hit an
			opponent with your Ghoul Bite natural weapon, you may cause that
			opponent to become [Sickened] for one [Round] and heal yourself %LVL% HP.
			A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Sickened] 
			condition and the healing. You also gain the Ghoul Bite natural weapon:
			Ghoul Bite – Melee, range [Melee], [Brutal 3]</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Unholy Regeneration" type="EX">You gain [Fast
			healing] %KDM%. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Flesh is Strong" type="EX">You gain
			[Immunity] to [Fear], [Bleeding], and the in-combat use of
			Intimidate. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Infected Bite" type="EX">Whenever you hit an
			opponent with an attack using your Ghoul Bite natural weapon, that
			opponent gains [Vulnerability] to physical damage for 1 [Round].
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Necrotic Aura" type="SU">Each opponent takes a
			penalty to all d20 rolls based on how close it is to you: a -3
			penalty within your [Melee] range, a -2 penalty within your [Close]
			range, and a -1 penalty within your [Medium] range. These penalties
			do not stack and expire as soon as the opponent leaves the area of
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Heartstopper" type="SU">You radiate an aura of
			decay. Any effect that would heal an opponent within [Medium] range
			heals %2*LVL% fewer points, to a minimum of 1 hit point healed.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Requiem" type="SU">Heroes who manage to
			strike you down are doomed to frustration. Once per [Scene], if you
			become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you return to undeath
			after 1 [Round] with full hit points. You may delay your revival or
			choose not to return at all. </circle>
	</track>
	<track bindId="undead" id="lich" name="Lich">
		<circle n="1" name="Undying Magecraft" type="EX">
			You draw strength from ambient magical energy. Whenever you cast a spell
			or spell-like ability, or an effect created by a spell or spell-like ability
			is ended by a [Dispelling] effect within [Close] range, you heal %LVL/2% HP,
			minimum 1. At will, as a standard action, you may also use Magic missile,
			as the spell, as a spell-like ability.</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Sorcerous Endurance" type="EX"> 
			Choose either [Cold] or [Electricity]. You gain [Resistance] to
			the chosen element. At 6th circle, this improves to [Resistance] to
			energy damage.</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Flesh is Strong" type="EX">You gain
			[Immunity] to [Fear], [Bleeding], and the in-combat use of
			Intimidate. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Hellfire Empowerment" type="SU"> You gain a +2
			bonus to the DCs of spells, spell-like abilities, and supernatural
			abilities you possess. Spells, spell-like abilities, and supernatural
			abilities you possess that have one or more targets within a range
			category may be used as if the range category within which you can
			choose your target(s) is one range category higher, to a maximum of
			[Extreme] range. Whenever an opponent is dealt damage by or fails a
			save against one of your spells, spell-like abilities, or
			supernatural abilities, you may cause that opponent to become
			[Burning]. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Necrotic Aura" type="SU">Each opponent takes a
			penalty to all d20 rolls based on how close it is to you: a -3
			penalty within your [Melee] range, a -2 penalty within your [Close]
			range, and a -1 penalty within your [Medium] range. These penalties
			do not stack and expire as soon as the opponent leaves the area of
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Arcane Insight" type="SLA">Once per [Encounter],
			as a swift action, you may use Greater dispel magic, as the spell.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Requiem" type="SU">Heroes who manage to
			strike you down are doomed to frustration. Once per [Scene], if you
			become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you return to undeath
			after 1 [Round] with full hit points. You may delay your revival or
			choose not to return at all. </circle>
	</track>
	<track bindId="undead" id="mummy" name="Mummy">
		<circle n="1" name="Growing Horror" type="SU">You draw strength from
			the fear of surrounding mortals. Every time an opponent within
			[Close] range fails a saving throw against a [Fear] effect, you
			regain %LVL% HP. The first opponent you hit each [Round]
			must make a Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) or become [Shaken] for one [Round]. 
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Well Embalmed" type="EX">You now feed on courage
			as well as fear. You gain [Lesser resistance] to physical damage.
			Whenever a creature other than yourself within [Close] range ignores
			a [Fear] effect due to an [Immunity] to [Fear], you regain %LVL/2% HP.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Flesh is Strong" type="EX">You gain
			[Immunity] to [Fear], [Bleeding], and the in-combat use of
			Intimidate. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Fear Aura" type="SU">For each opponent, the
			first time that opponent begins its turn within or enters your
			[Melee] range in an [Encounter], you may choose to give that opponent
			a terrifying gaze that causes that opponent to become [Shaken]. A
			successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Shaken] condition. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Necrotic Aura" type="SU">Each opponent takes a
			penalty to all d20 rolls based on how close it is to you: a -3
			penalty within your [Melee] range, a -2 penalty within your [Close]
			range, and a -1 penalty within your [Medium] range. These penalties
			do not stack and expire as soon as the opponent leaves the area of
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Contagious Touch" type="SU">As a standard
			action, you may make a single attack. On a hit, you deal damage as
			normal and inflict a -3 penalty to attack rolls and a -5 penalty to
			damage until the end of the [Encounter]. A successful Fortitude save
			(DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates these penalties. Additionally, once per [Round],
			as a swift action, you may inflict a -3 penalty to attack rolls
			and a -5 penalty to damage until the end of the [Encounter] on any creature
			within %5+5*LVL/5% ft of a creature already penalized by Contagious
			Touch. A successful Fortitude save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates these penalties.
		</circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Requiem" type="SU">Heroes who manage to
			strike you down are doomed to frustration. Once per [Scene], if you
			become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you return to undeath
			after 1 [Round] with full hit points. You may delay your revival or
			choose not to return at all. </circle>
	</track>
	<track bindId="undead" id="vampire" name="Vampire">
		<circle n="1" name="Bloodlust" type="SU">You draw strength from
			feeding on blood. Whenever you deal damage with your Vampire Bite
			natural weapon, you heal half the damage dealt, to a maximum of %KOM%.
			Abilities or effects that would increase this ability’s healing do so
			only once per [Round]. You gain the Vampire Bite natural weapon: 
			Vampire Bite – Melee, range [Melee], [Brutal 2], [Magnum]. </circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Discorporation" type="SU">At will, as a swift
			action, you can turn into a swarm of bats, mist, or similar form to
			move between opponents and around obstacles (and even through cracks
			in walls) with ease. For one [Round], you do not provoke attacks of
			opportunity while moving and gain the Fly movement mode. You may
			enter occupied squares, but if you end your movement in an occupied
			square, you are shunted to the last unoccupied square you entered.
		</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Flesh is Strong" type="EX">You gain
			[Immunity] to [Fear], [Bleeding], and the in-combat use of
			Intimidate. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Entrancing Gaze" type="SLA"> Once per
			[Encounter], as a standard action, you may gain the effects of a
			Sanctuary spell with a DC of %10+LVL/2+KOM% and cause all opponents 
			within [Close] range to become [Confused] for three [Rounds].
			A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%) negates the [Confused]
			condition. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Necrotic Aura" type="SU">Each opponent takes a
			penalty to all d20 rolls based on how close it is to you: a -3
			penalty within your [Melee] range, a -2 penalty within your [Close]
			range, and a -1 penalty within your [Medium] range. These penalties
			do not stack and expire as soon as the opponent leaves the area of
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Child of Shadows" type="SU">You gain [Fast
			healing] %LVL%. In addition, you may now use your Discorporation
			ability as a free action. Whenever you use Discorporation, 
			for one [Round], whenever you move, you may make any
			opponent within [Melee] range of your movement path [Shaken] for the
			rest of the [Encounter]. A successful Will save (DC %10+LVL/2+KOM%)
			negates the [Shaken] condition. You may only make each opponent
			[Shaken] with this ability once per [Encounter]. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Requiem" type="SU">Heroes who manage to
			strike you down are doomed to frustration. Once per [Scene], if you
			become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you return to undeath
			after 1 [Round] with full hit points. You may delay your revival or
			choose not to return at all. </circle>
	</track>
	<track bindId="undead" id="skeletonChampion" name="Skeleton Champion">
		<circle n="1" name="Devastating Strike" type="SU"> At the beginning
			of an [Encounter], you gain a focus point. Once per [Round], when an
			ally in [Close] range activates a spell, spell-like, or supernatural
			ability, takes an offensive action, or is affected by an offensive
			action, you gain a focus point. In addition, you may spend 3 focus
			points during an attack action to make a [Bonus attack] and heal %LVL% HP.</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Rattling Bones" type="SU">Once per
			[Round], as a swift action, as long as you possess at least 1 point
			of focus, you may gain a +2 bonus to your next attack roll, and deal
			%KOM% additional energy damage with the [Acid], [Cold], [Electricity], or
			[Fire] whenever you deal damage with an attack for one [Round]. </circle>
		<circle n="3" name="The Flesh is Strong" type="EX">You gain
			[Immunity] to [Fear], [Bleeding], and the in-combat use of
			Intimidate. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Fury of the Dead" type="EX">Once per [Round],
			you may replace one attack from your attack action with the Bull
			Rush, Disarm, or Trip combat maneuver. The Disarm and Trip combat
			maneuvers are made with the same attack bonus as the replaced attack.
		</circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Necrotic Aura" type="SU">Each opponent takes a
			penalty to all d20 rolls based on how close it is to you: a -3
			penalty within your [Melee] range, a -2 penalty within your [Close]
			range, and a -1 penalty within your [Medium] range. These penalties
			do not stack and expire as soon as the opponent leaves the area of
			effect. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Eternal Warrior" type="EX">You gain [Lesser
			resistance] to all damage. Whenever you would be dealt damage, you
			can spend a focus point to increase your [Lesser resistance] from
			this ability to [Resistance] against that damage, or two focus points
			to increase your [Lesser resistance] from this ability to [Greater
			resistance] against that damage. </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="No Requiem" type="SU">Heroes who manage to
			strike you down are doomed to frustration. Once per [Scene], if you
			become [Dead] or are rendered [Unconscious], you return to undeath
			after 1 [Round] with full hit points. You may delay your revival or
			choose not to return at all. </circle>
	</track>
	<track id="utterBrute" name="Utter Brute">
		<circle n="1" name="Uncivilized" type="EX">You gain the following
			natural weapon: Hulking Smash: Melee, range [Melee], [Brutal 2],
			[Reach]In addition, select one of the following abilities:
			-Defender: You gain a bonus that is both fury and item to Armor Class
			equal to the higher of +2 or %CRL%. -Attacker: You gain a +%CRL% bonus that is
			both fury and item to your attack rolls.
		</circle>
		<circle n="2" name="Unforgiving" type="EX">The first time you hit
			with an attack each [Round], after dealing damage, you deal [HP
			reduction] equal to that amount of damage, up to your character
			level. In addition, once per [Encounter], when you would become
			[Dead], you may first take a standard action. You are still [Dead]
			after taking the action, so healing won’t help you, and you can’t
			activate abilities to resurrect yourself if you opt to activate
			Unforgiving. Triggered abilities with no action cost may be activated
			instead of the standard action.</circle>
		<circle n="3" name="Unrelenting" type="EX">At the beginning of your
			turn, you may move 5 ft. At the end of your turn, you may move 5 ft.
			Effects and conditions other than [Dead] that prevent movement do not
			prevent this. If you are [Grappled], or [Pinned], this movement
			causes the creature grappling or pinning you to move 5 ft in the same
			direction, and does not end the [Grappled] or [Pinned] condition.
			This movement does not provoke attacks of opportunity. </circle>
		<circle n="4" name="Unnatural" type="EX">Select a set of bonuses
			from the following. These bonuses are fury bonuses. 
			-Soldier: You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and Fortitude saves, 
			a +%LVL*3% bonus to your maximum hit points, and a +10 ft bonus to your movement speed. 
			-Striker: You gain a +3 bonus to attack rolls and Fortitude saves, 
			a +%LVL*3% bonus to your maximum hit points, and a +5 ft bonus to your [Melee] range.
			-Skirmisher: You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and Fortitude saves, 
			a +%LVL% bonus to your maximum hit points, a +15 ft bonus to your movement speed,
			and a +5 ft bonus to your [Melee] range. </circle>
		<circle n="5" name="Unspeakable" type="EX">Choose two of the
			following abilities (these choices are permanent): -Flight: You gain
			the Fly movement mode. -Focus: You can eavesdrop on telepathic
			communication if any participant is within [Close] range. »
			Flexibility: Your [Melee] range is increased by 10 ft. -Flesh: You
			gain [Fast healing] %LVL%. </circle>
		<circle n="6" name="Unbreakable" type="EX">You gain [Immunity] to
			two of the following: [Stunned], [Dazed], [Prone], [Slowed], [Fear]
			effects (this includes [Shaken], [Frightened], [Panicked] and
			[Cowering]). </circle>
		<circle n="7" name="Unstoppable" type="EX">You gain [Immunity] to
			[Unconscious] and [Dying], though you still die at -%10+2*CON%
			HP. Additionally, every time you hit an opponent with an attack, you
			may move that opponent 5 ft in any direction. </circle>
	</track>
</root>